<overherd><post><title>New to the Chicago Board? Read This First</title><id>4090768</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:42:00</time><content>
 Are you new to Chowhound? Or just to the Chicago board? Perhaps visiting from out of town? We've got some tips to help you get started.  If you're brand new to the site, you should read our Site Etiquette (</content><char_count>208</char_count><word_count>42</word_count><reply><id>4090773</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:43:00</time><content>
 HAVE A HOT TIP?
If you've got a great tip or a recommendation for someone, dive right in and post it. It's great if you can include some details of why you like a place, but even those short tips on where to find a great taco or donut are appreciated.   If you need help starting a new thread, check out the FAQ: </content><char_count>315</char_count><word_count>66</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090777</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:43:00</time><content>
 HAVE A QUESTION?
The Chicago board is a pretty active place, and a lot of questions have been covered recently--the Chowhound archives are a great resource.  Start your quest for an answer with a search of all the great info that's already out there. The search box is in the top right corner of the screen. If you're searching from this board, it should default to searching Chicago. Just add your keywords and go. On the search results page, you can change your search criteria to add more keywords, or change your sort order or the dates you're interested in. 
</content><char_count>566</char_count><word_count>102</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090778</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:43:00</time><content>
 FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS ON THE CHICAGO BOARD
(and how to find the answers)  These topics are all commonly discussed on the Chicago board, so we'd encourage you to read through some of the recent discussions before posting about them.   Where's the best Chicago Style Pizza / Hot Dog / Italian Beef?
Search terms to try: title:pizza or title:"deep dish" / title:"hot dog" / title:"italian beef". These are much debated and discussed issues on the board, so your searches will turn up lots of results. Try adding a neighborhood name for more localized results.    What's the best Steakhouse in Chicago?
Search terms to try: title:steakhouse OR title:steak  Where should we eat in the Loop?
Search terms to try: title:Loop, "Grant Park", "Millennium Park", "Palmer House"  Where should we eat near Michigan Avenue?
Search terms to try: "Michigan Ave", "Magnificent Mile", Streeterville, "River North"  Where should we eat near McCormick Place?
Search terms to try: "McCormick Place", "Convention Center", "South Loop", Chinatown  Where should we eat near Wrigley Field?
Search terms to try: Wrigley Field, Lakeview, Wrigleyville 
</content><char_count>1132</char_count><word_count>180</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090779</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 STILL HAVE A QUESTION?  Chicago hounds are a great resource, but help them help you by including some important details. Tell them:  - What part of what city you'll be in.
- How far or how long you're willing to travel and whether you will have a car.
- What your budget is. Descriptions such as 'expensive', 'moderate' and 'cheap' mean different things to different people, so use dollar values.
- What types of cuisines you're interested in.
- Any other special circumstances (traveling with kids? vegetarians? non-chowhounds?) that will help.  If you've done some of your own research, mention what you found so hounds can help fill in the gaps, rather than rehashing what you already know. 
</content><char_count>697</char_count><word_count>119</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090783</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 AFTER YOUR MEAL
Most importantly, after your trip or your meal, thank the local hounds for their help by reporting back. Tell people which suggestions you used and how the meals turned out, plus add tips about any great places you discovered on your own. This helps makes the board more useful for everyone who visits after you. 
</content><char_count>332</char_count><word_count>59</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090786</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 CHICAGO SPECIFICS   For information on how to get to various restaurants on public transit, check out the Trip Planner at </content><char_count>124</char_count><word_count>24</word_count></reply><reply><id>4090788</id><author>The Chowhound Team</author><date>2008-10-08</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 FEEDBACK
If there's something you think is vitally important for new members of the board to know that we've missed, please comment on this Site Talk thread: </content><char_count>160</char_count><word_count>28</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Need help deciding on one restaurant</title><id>6212034</id><author>jhojati</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>15:56:00</time><content>
 I'll be in Chicago Friday the 21st.  There are restaurants on my list to do in Chicago, but Girl &amp; the Goat, Topolo, and </content><char_count>123</char_count><word_count>27</word_count><reply><id>6212209</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>16:48:00</time><content>
 Sounds like you've already been doing a lot of research; that's a pretty good list of choices.  Since you've mentioned a list of places, here are my reactions to the ones you've listed:  Sable (maybe just for a cocktail?) - I love Sable.  The food is fantastic, and a lot of the menu items are available in smaller portions as well as full ones, so you can try more things.  If you go, don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee.  However, I wouldn't refer to it as romantic or quiet, although it's certainly casual; the decor is contemporary and the noise level is high.  Yes, it would also work for a cocktail, especially if it's close by the place you end up choosing.  Graham Elliott - I haven't been there.  North Pond - This would be my top pick of those you've listed.  The setting and atmosphere in the park are extra special (and romantic), and the food is excellent.  Make your reservation NOW as they do fill up on weekends.  Cafe des Architectes - CdA built its reputation in the past couple of years on the strength of its executive chef, Martial Noguier.  However, he left there a couple of months ago (soon to head the replacement for Eve).  I had brunch there a week ago and it was still great, but I can only guess that they're sort of "running on autopilot" until a new chef takes charge.  So I'd probably go elsewhere for your one dinner.  OTOH if you're still around for brunch on Saturday, it's a very good choice for that.  (I loved the "brunch sampler".)   Avenues - This is one of our finest restaurants, and also one of our most expensive and formal (i.e. jackets required).  I haven't been there under the current chef Duffy.  David Burke - A great choice if you want the best steak in town, but if you're looking for something else, maybe not.  Mercat a la Planxa - A fun experience with food that's unusual.  The room and atmosphere are lively.  avec - Unless you're willing to put up with a no-reservations policy with waits of 60-120 minutes, a VERY LOUD noise level, communal-only seating, and the most uncomfortable seats anywhere, I don't recommend it.  Table Fifty-Two - I haven't been there, as the menu on their website hasn't enticed me.  Reserve NOW as this is another place that fills up in advance.  Bottom line, North Pond would be my top pick IF you can get a reservation there, otherwise Sable.  Among the other choices, Avenues or Burke's or Mercat if you're looking for high-end, steaks, or tapas, respectively.  Or maybe try one of the places I haven't been.  If you're looking for additional suggestions, you might also consider contemporary Italian at Cibo Matto, Vivere, or the Florentine.  I would also consider Aria, which is in the Fairmont a block from the Hyatt; they serve a global menu with some Asian influences.  (If there's a big snowstorm that day, the proximity of Aria will make getting there a whole lot easier, so it may be something to consider as a possible backup plan.) 
</content><char_count>2937</char_count><word_count>556</word_count><reply><id>6212267</id><author>jhojati</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>17:09:00</time><content>
 Really quite helpful.  I'll report back on my trip.  I can get an 8:30 reso at </content><char_count>81</char_count><word_count>20</word_count></reply><reply><id>6212395</id><author>jhojati</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>17:57:00</time><content>
 I've seen a lot of pub for Sunda...worth the hype? 
</content><char_count>54</char_count><word_count>12</word_count><reply><id>6212418</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>18:08:00</time><content>
 I haven't been there, sorry.  I've heard mixed reviews from friends, mostly good about the food, not so good about the "scene", but it's second hand.  Maybe someone else here can provide actual personal experience... 
</content><char_count>220</char_count><word_count>39</word_count><reply><id>6213455</id><author>lbs</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>07:11:00</time><content>
 Sunda was on Check Please* last Friday and got really favorable reviews.     * Check Please is the local PBS show in which 3 people pick a restaurant and then review them.   If the place is favorably reviewed, often a "Check Please" effect happens and it gets really crowded.    Link below with the episode info.  </content><char_count>316</char_count><word_count>66</word_count><reply><id>6213553</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>07:40:00</time><content>
 Topolobampo accepts reservations three months in advance, and dinner reservations book up very quickly.  They're usually booked solid by about two months out.  You may get lucky with a last-minute cancellation, and as you say it doesn't hurt to check, but don't count on it.  Lunch is often a better bet; lunch books up a couple weeks out, and Friday books up before other days.  A week out, it's unlikely.  You can always go to Frontera Grill, which only accepts a few reservations and keeps most of its dining room available for walk-in traffic, but unless you arrive at Frontera 20-30 minutes before they open the doors, you're looking at a long wait to be seated (60-120 minutes).  I tried going there for their Saturday brunch a couple of months ago and the wait was 90 minutes.  If you're interested in upscale creative Mexican cuisine, there are other options with great food, including Salpicon in Old Town, Mundial Cocina Mestiza in Pilsen, and Mexique in West Town. 
</content><char_count>979</char_count><word_count>176</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6214286</id><author>ms. mika</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 I love Sunda- it's one of my favorite places to go- it has really delicious food and a fun atmosphere, but it wouldn't fall under a quiet or romantic type place- it's a little more trendy and lively in terms of atmosphere.
Other places I would throw out as suggestions would be </content><char_count>280</char_count><word_count>53</word_count><reply><id>6216031</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>21:48:00</time><content>
 Good idea suggesting </content><char_count>23</char_count><word_count>5</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6220519</id><author>jhojati</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>20:52:00</time><content>
 Thanks again for all the feedback - I need to decide quickly, but also need time to marinate a bit on the decision.  A couple quick followups:  1.  Any Accanto experiences?  I've read some good things, some not so good.
2.  I'll be in Schaumburg Thursday night - any suggestions for something low key? 
</content><char_count>305</char_count><word_count>60</word_count><reply><id>6220865</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>06:04:00</time><content>
 I'm not familiar with Accanto.  If you're specifically looking for Italian cuisine, here are the places I'd concentrate on: Cafe Spiaggia, Cibo Matto, Vivere, Coco Pazzo, Piccolo Sogno, and the Florentine.  Here are places I like in and around Schaumburg:  Shaw's Crab House (Schaumburg) - Some of Chicago's best seafood in the atmosphere of an old-time New England seafood restaurant.  </content><char_count>389</char_count><word_count>66</word_count><reply><id>6225340</id><author>jhojati</author><date>2011-01-18</date><time>14:17:00</time><content>
 Seriously, you get around!  Awesome recommendations again.  Thank you. 
</content><char_count>74</char_count><word_count>13</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6221230</id><author>mountsac</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>08:47:00</time><content>
 Per nsxtasy's list, I concur on the Thai places, the two steak places, and Lou.  There are also some other good ethnic options in the area: Korean (Woo Lae Oak), Japanese (Kurumaya, Daruma), and Indian (Priya, India House).    I will, however, avoid Le Titi de Paris.  It is highly overrated IMO.  I've only been there once, and it was the second most disappointing dining experience I've had in Chicagoland (first being Charlie Trotter's).   On the day I was there, neither the service nor the food was up to par.  Maybe it was an off-day, but why risk it when you have other safe alternatives? 
</content><char_count>599</char_count><word_count>115</word_count><reply><id>6221299</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>09:09:00</time><content>
 I've been to Le Titi de Paris numerous times for both lunch and dinner, and it has always been superb for the food as well as the service.  I will be dining there again next weekend as part of their Chicago Originals Restaurant Week promotion and will report here afterwards, but even before doing so, I can assure you that your one bad experience was not typical. 
</content><char_count>368</char_count><word_count>70</word_count><reply><id>6221414</id><author>suzieq4</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>09:44:00</time><content>
 When you get a reservation at </content><char_count>32</char_count><word_count>8</word_count><reply><id>6221735</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>11:24:00</time><content>
 The room you're referring to is not really an enclosed porch or patio.  It's a regular room that's part of the building's structure.  It features full length (floor to ceiling) windows and I don't know for sure but they might be "French doors" that open during the warm months of the year.  So you can ask for the front room facing the pond.  (I've also dined in the inner room, with the open kitchen along the rear, and it's also very nice and pleasant, but it doesn't have the view of the pond and people walking by.) 
</content><char_count>523</char_count><word_count>103</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Where to buy German wines in the Chicagoland area</title><id>6221402</id><author>suzieq4</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>09:40:00</time><content>
 I just returned from Germany and had some nice red and white German wines while I was traveling. Most of the wine stores I go to in Chgo don't have a great selection of German wines.  I would like to buy rieslings that are minerally and not sweet.  I also had a nice red -Lemberger trocken and Spatburgunder from Ahr. I also would like to purchase good trockenbeereauseleses and eisweins.  Any suggestions would be appreciated. Thanks. 
</content><char_count>439</char_count><word_count>81</word_count><reply><id>6221598</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>10:36:00</time><content>
 try house of glunz or whatever it's called, over by there on Wells 2, 3 doors north of Division. 
</content><char_count>100</char_count><word_count>21</word_count></reply><reply><id>6221782</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>11:38:00</time><content>
 Binny's has quite a nice selection of German wines.  </content><char_count>55</char_count><word_count>12</word_count><reply><id>6223085</id><author>suzieq4</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>18:52:00</time><content>
 Thanks - my Binnys doesn't seem to have that good of a German wine selection.  Maybe others do. I live in the western suburbs so I will check when I am near north.  Maybe they have a better selection.  Yes, I know about the Michigan icewines and have purchased some of them.  I was wondering if there are any stores in Chicago selling German eisweins. I will check out Coopershawkwinery. 
</content><char_count>391</char_count><word_count>76</word_count><reply><id>6224376</id><author>rjka</author><date>2011-01-18</date><time>09:36:00</time><content>
 The couple of Binny's I have been to north of the city do not have a good selection of German wines either . In my recollection, neither does Schaefer's, but I haven't been there in a couple of years so things might have changed or my memory is fuzzy. As another fan of German wInes, I too have been frustrated and will be interested to see if any good shops turn up. 
</content><char_count>371</char_count><word_count>74</word_count></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Late bite near Steppenwolf</title><id>6219792</id><author>BaraXan</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>15:31:00</time><content>
 Visiting from out of town and going to the theater Tuesday night.  I'd like to have a late supper and drink afterwards, between the theater and the north shore, where I'm staying. Maybe a place that serves at the bar? Thanks for any suggestions. 
</content><char_count>249</char_count><word_count>47</word_count><reply><id>6223923</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-18</date><time>06:57:00</time><content>
 There are many places that might be suitable.  Give us an idea of what you're looking for.
In the immediate area is </content><char_count>118</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6223993</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-18</date><time>07:23:00</time><content>
 But some of those places aren't open late.  The latest seating at Boka is 9:00, and at Cafe Ba-Ba-Reeba is 9:30.  Goose Island might be a better bet; the dining room closes at 10:00 but the bar stays open till 11:00 with a limited menu. 
</content><char_count>240</char_count><word_count>49</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Celebrating Julia Child: New Menu - Chopping Block</title><id>6220813</id><author>ldubois2</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>05:24:00</time><content>
 Today I am going to the Chopping Block for a morning hands-on cooking class.  I've been before but not in a few years and have never been to their new locations.  This is a new class.....I'll report back.  Menu from Mastering the Art of French Cooking  Soup &#224; l'Oignon Gratin&#233;e (French Onion Soup); Beef Daube (Beef Braised with Red Wine, Mushrooms and Tomatoes); Celery Root Puree; Tart Normande Aux Pommes (Apple Custard Tart). 
</content><char_count>433</char_count><word_count>79</word_count><reply><id>6222199</id><author>ldubois2</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>13:39:00</time><content>
 Okay....back from Chopping Block.  Great class...Nick taught proper technique for mise en plas, knife skills, and walked through each step of the meal preparation.  Best thing I learned: what caramelized onions actually look like.  I have never cooked them as slowly or as long as necessary.  Also had two assistants bringing ingredients, tools and gathering for cleanup.  Chopping Block offers a 10% discount for anything in the store and a 15% discount on all items used in the recipe.  Recommend 
</content><char_count>502</char_count><word_count>88</word_count><reply><id>6222218</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>13:44:00</time><content>
 Most important question: How did the food taste? 
</content><char_count>52</char_count><word_count>10</word_count><reply><id>6222356</id><author>lbs</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>14:26:00</time><content>
 Second important question:  what Chopping Block?  The one at the Merch Mart or the one in Lincoln Square?  I'm intrigued. 
</content><char_count>125</char_count><word_count>25</word_count><reply><id>6222849</id><author>ldubois2</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>17:23:00</time><content>
 Lincoln Square.  Wanted to go to the Sausage store accross the street but ran out of time.  Reminiscent of the original location. 
</content><char_count>133</char_count><word_count>26</word_count><reply><id>6223952</id><author>lbs</author><date>2011-01-18</date><time>07:11:00</time><content>
 That is great to hear that it was at the L.S location.  I live right by there and my interest is definitely perked.    Thank you for the report! 
</content><char_count>148</char_count><word_count>34</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6222845</id><author>ldubois2</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>17:22:00</time><content>
 Soup had good flavor.  Daube was excellent.  Never tried celery root before and it is a vegetable I'd use again.  I liked it's addition to the Daube (plated on the celery root puree).  Tart was a little rough.  Three people were slicing apples and each had a different idea of how thinly to chop.  It was inconsistent in texture.  Over all great.  My plan is to do this Sunday. 
</content><char_count>381</char_count><word_count>79</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6222596</id><author>beanbreath</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>16:02:00</time><content>
 I'm glad you enjoyed yourself and, hopefully, learned something.
Obviously it wasn't the correct spelling of 'mise en place'.  On the local front, my wife is, tonight, attemptin a French onion soup, started with the roasted bones from a couple of beef shanks and those from the left over pork ribs last night.
I bowed out of the kitchen, thinking about ordering sushi.  On a Monday night. 
</content><char_count>392</char_count><word_count>69</word_count><reply><id>6222866</id><author>ldubois2</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>17:29:00</time><content>
 Gracias for the correction )  If nothing else, I learned how to spell ;)  Yes...learned what caramelized onions look like...if you've never experienced what they look like it is easy to think they are ready when they are not.  Never worked in a restaurant and my mom was a Campbell's soup and ground beef cook.  I love to cook and have learned from books and doing it myself.  I live a distance from cooking classes.  I have made sushi in the past....not too terribly difficult.  But fun! 
</content><char_count>492</char_count><word_count>96</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Brasserie Jo on West Hubbard carrot crudite</title><id>5749013</id><author>javaandjazz</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>07:04:00</time><content>
 Had a very nice dinner at Brasserie Jo on West Hubbard last night. I just have to say the carrot crudite they brought out was a real surprise. I have always liked carrots but now I LIKE them even more. I told our wait person how good they were and he offered the recipe. I can't wait to get home and make them now. I'm from CT. Also, their mac &amp; cheese was very good too. We were told they are closing soon and that maybe another french restaurant will reopen in that space. I hope that if I ever come back to Chicago, I will have the oppurtunity to try the new place. 
</content><char_count>572</char_count><word_count>116</word_count><reply><id>5749163</id><author>ellenost</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>08:26:00</time><content>
 My sister and I recently returned home to NYC from Chicago and also had dinner at Brasserie Jo.  We thought the carrot crudite was amazing.  We asked for a second portion.  The restaurant is lovely and it's a shame that they're closing.  We loved the onion soup.  I ordered the hanger steak with fries, and was disappointed.  The fries were too crispy (had the texture and taste of canned potato sticks--not french fries), and the steak was very chewy (yes, I do know the texture of hanger steak, and this wasn't it). 
</content><char_count>521</char_count><word_count>100</word_count></reply><reply><id>5749301</id><author>twodales</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>09:35:00</time><content>
 Intrigued about the carrot crudite?  What made it so special?  What was it made of besides carrots?  Was there a dijon-ish vinaigrette? 
</content><char_count>139</char_count><word_count>27</word_count><reply><id>5749312</id><author>ellenost</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>09:39:00</time><content>
 It had a horseradish dressing. 
</content><char_count>34</char_count><word_count>7</word_count><reply><id>5750513</id><author>javaandjazz</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>20:07:00</time><content>
 It was the horse radish that made it. I love horse radish! It was slighly subtle but you could definitely taste it. 
</content><char_count>119</char_count><word_count>24</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>5750321</id><author>Masonville</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>18:38:00</time><content>
 Possibly no connection whatsover, but I do recall one of the very early LEYE restaurants, 1972ish, just south of what's now the Viagra Triangle, that served, among other interesting appetizers, a perfect carrot crudite.  I had just returned from my first trip to Paris--which was then still stellar despite some (prescient) prophets of decline.  I wish I could remember the name--it may have been The Flying Frenchman, but Google has not unearthed its corpse.  In any case, perhaps somewhere in the LEYE archives is the one true recipe for a shredded carrot crudite. 
</content><char_count>570</char_count><word_count>98</word_count><reply><id>5750847</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-07-12</date><time>04:02:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; I wish I could remember the name--it may have been The Flying Frenchman  I believe you're referring to Great Gritzbe's Flying Food Show. 
</content><char_count>143</char_count><word_count>27</word_count><reply><id>5751758</id><author>ferret</author><date>2010-07-12</date><time>10:18:00</time><content>
 And it opened closer to the mid-70's. 
</content><char_count>41</char_count><word_count>9</word_count><reply><id>5751988</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-07-12</date><time>11:24:00</time><content>
 1974, according to the LEY website at </content><char_count>40</char_count><word_count>9</word_count><reply><id>5752717</id><author>ferret</author><date>2010-07-12</date><time>14:44:00</time><content>
 I recalled it being a high school thing (I started in 1974) while Fritz's opened while I was still in elementary school. 
</content><char_count>124</char_count><word_count>24</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>5762221</id><author>Masonville</author><date>2010-07-15</date><time>18:30:00</time><content>
 OK, nsxtasy, you're right.  I needed a few days to process the memories.  The Flying Frenchman was within a few blocks, but was a quite different animal altogether.  Anyway, I have to say Gritzbe's was a seriously "authentic" place, which I say despite my usual skepticism/contempt for that commonplace.  Which leads me to a general comment about LEYE:  it's obviously vulnerable to the accusation that it's the restaurant equivalent of DisneyWorld.  I'm not entirely sure that's a negative, altho I'm inclined to think so.  But it doesn't stick w/ LEYE.  In many if not most instances, Melman does an amazing job of getting it right and doing it better than most.  Certainly in 1973 (and that's when I first went to Gritzbe's), he had a better handle on French bistro cuisine than anyone else in Chicago. 
</content><char_count>809</char_count><word_count>147</word_count><reply><id>5762257</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-07-15</date><time>18:46:00</time><content>
 I have tremendous respect for Lettuce Entertain You.  They have brought a high level of quality to all their concepts.  What's really amazing, though, is what a broad range of concepts they have created - everything from fine dining to cheap eats, from ethnic food to mainstream.  I doubt that there is any restaurant company anywhere in the country that has done so many different things so well. 
</content><char_count>401</char_count><word_count>73</word_count><reply><id>5763768</id><author>JPea</author><date>2010-07-16</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 Interesting discussion but too much misinformation and misinterpretation. How 'bout some &quot;true facts&quot;?  The Flying Frenchman and Great Gritzbe's Flying Food Show were at the same location, the southwest corner of Wabash and Chestnut. The Flying Frenchman opened in late 1969; Great Gritzbe's opened in late 1974.  The Flying Frenchman was owned by Bill Contos of Chez Paul fame. When they opened they featured crepes and other simple French standards. But around 1971 Jean Banchet took over the kitchen and transformed the restaurant, if only briefly. Of course, Chef Banchet would go on to helm the great Le Francais which he opened in early 1973. Anyone dining at The Flying Frenchman in the early '70s was witnessing the early evolution of a great chef. It's not surprising the carrot crudite was memorable (by the way, how was the rest of the meal?). Congratulations on recognizing genius and thanks for sharing your memories with us.  Great Gritzbe's, Lettuce Entertain You's third restaurant, served French toast, French onion soup and French fries but it surely was not a French restaurant. Their menu, largely sandwiches and gimmicky drinks, was far closer to R J Grunt's (Lettuce Entertain You's first restaurant) than to The Flying Frenchman's. One of Great Gritzbe's contributions to the culinary scene was an all-you-can-eat dessert bar, following Grunt's successful salad buffet.  Lettuce Entertain You is getting far too much credit when people attribute introducing sophisticated French cuisine to Chicago in the early 1970s. Back then&#8212;their salad days, if you will&#8212;they were busy trying to replicate the success of R J Grunt's. It was only later they got around to trying to replicate other country's cuisines. Their first attempt at foreign food (not very successful in my opinion) was Lawrence of Oregano in 1976, serving massive portions of Italian-American classics. One could argue they hit their stride in the 1980s with Ambria and a string of other foreign restaurants including Cafe Ba-Ba-Reeba. I'm not at all trying to deny the importance of Lettuce Entertain You in the development of the Chicago (and national) dining scene but let's have some historical accuracy.  To get back to the original topic, can anyone provide details of Brasserie Jo's carrot crudite? It sounds really good and I'm not sure I'll be able to get back to the restaurant before it closes. 
</content><char_count>2393</char_count><word_count>393</word_count><reply><id>5763900</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-07-16</date><time>11:22:00</time><content>
 I wasn't sure where you were coming from, JPea, until I re-read the post to which you were replying, and saw this statement:  &gt;&gt; Certainly in 1973 (and that's when I first went to Gritzbe's), he had a better handle on French bistro cuisine than anyone else in Chicago.  I agree with you, JPea, that Great Gritzbe's was not French in any way.  If anyone had the best handle on French bistro cuisine at that time, it was Kiki, who opened Le Bordeaux on Madison in the Loop in 1969.  In the early 1970s it was the only French restaurant in the Loop, and featured classic French bistro cuisine (which Kiki is still serving today at his eponymous bistro in River North).  Walking down those few steps into Le Bordeaux was like being transported from the Loop to the French countryside.  Of course there were also high-end French restaurants in town as well, such as the ones from the late Jovan Trboyevic (Jovan opened in 1967 and Le Perroquet in 1973). 
</content><char_count>952</char_count><word_count>179</word_count></reply><reply><id>5764630</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2010-07-16</date><time>15:16:00</time><content>
 "their salad days"   LOL! 
</content><char_count>29</char_count><word_count>8</word_count></reply><reply><id>6177528</id><author>potatoes</author><date>2011-01-01</date><time>12:04:00</time><content>
 Thanks, Chandraram.  Can you give us the measurements of each ingredient? 
</content><char_count>77</char_count><word_count>14</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6223350</id><author>LindaRacine</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>20:51:00</time><content>
 This is sort of off topic, but does anyone remember the name of the restaurant that was on the 7th floor of Water Tower Place when they first opened the retail space?  They served things like sandwiches, salads, omelets, etc.  They had the most menu items I'd ever seen (until Cheesecake Factory maybe).  I thought it was a LEYE restaurant, but I could be mistaken. 
</content><char_count>369</char_count><word_count>70</word_count><reply><id>6223456</id><author>twodales</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>21:53:00</time><content>
 I think it might have been a LEVY restaurant. Think it was their first restaurant.  Was it D. B. Kaplans? 
</content><char_count>109</char_count><word_count>23</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6177574</id><author>greygarious</author><date>2011-01-01</date><time>12:24:00</time><content>
 Jandj, since you are in CT you might like to know that there is a Brasserie Jo in Boston's Colonnade Hotel. 
</content><char_count>111</char_count><word_count>23</word_count></reply><reply><id>6178149</id><author>javaandjazz</author><date>2011-01-01</date><time>17:09:00</time><content>
 this is right from the restaurant.  Brasserie JO Carrot Crudites    
2 lbs. carrots 
1 tbsp. fresh grated horseradish 
2 tbsp, prepared horseradish 
1 clove of garlic chopped 
1 tbsp. Diion mustard 
4 tbsp. melior vinegar 
2 tbsp. olive oil 
l~ cup chopped parsley 
salt &amp; freshly ground pepper 
Preparation: 
1.	Peel and Cut carrots in 4 in. long sticks. Set aside in cold water for 
approximately 1 hour. 
2.	Drain and pat dry very well. Put in bowl and add all remaining 
ingredients. Toss verywell together. Season to taste with salt and pepper. 
Set aside for approximately 2 hours before serving to ensure carrots 
absorb all seasoning. 
3.	Serve in a small serving dish. 
Note: This is a pe~if'd snack that goes very Jvell with Alsace wine or a beer. This tuas a 
favorite if Chif Joho ~\ grandparents. IjYON cannot find me!for vinegar, use a nice tuhite zvine 
vinegar as a substitnte. 
</content><char_count>897</char_count><word_count>156</word_count><reply><id>6182342</id><author>potatoes</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>13:22:00</time><content>
 Thank you! 
</content><char_count>14</char_count><word_count>4</word_count><reply><id>6182399</id><author>javaandjazz</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>13:41:00</time><content>
 Good luck. I haven't made them at home yet and it's been since July 2010 since I have had them. 
</content><char_count>99</char_count><word_count>22</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6220592</id><author>stellamystar</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>21:39:00</time><content>
 I made these about 6 months ago and they were fab! I used white wine vinegar and regular ole horseradish. The dressing is also great for salad!  I still think they're better there, but these are great for home! 
</content><char_count>214</char_count><word_count>42</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Chicken Wings</title><id>6219942</id><author>hmg2814</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>16:36:00</time><content>
 When a restaurant's menu mentions "24 chicken wings", should you expect 24 whole chicken wings, or 24 segments of a chicken's wing? 
</content><char_count>135</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6220009</id><author>Breezychow</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>17:03:00</time><content>
 24 chicken wing segments, not 24 whole wings. 
</content><char_count>49</char_count><word_count>10</word_count><reply><id>6220062</id><author>Cheez62</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>17:24:00</time><content>
 +1 for the answer of segments.  Can't recall the last time I was at a place where the whole wing was served, though I have been a few places where the second segment (not the "drumette") is served with the tip attached.  Not much meat added, but some good crunchy bits if properly fried. 
</content><char_count>291</char_count><word_count>58</word_count><reply><id>6221607</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>10:37:00</time><content>
 And now that you all got me in the mood, where would one get such crunchy and delicious chicken wings?  Used to go to that place on Howard but it's not convenient any more.  LP, Lakeview area. 
</content><char_count>196</char_count><word_count>41</word_count><reply><id>6222453</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>15:00:00</time><content>
 I tried Wing Stop and thought it was horrible.  Buffalo Joe's in Evanston is very good. 
</content><char_count>91</char_count><word_count>19</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6222330</id><author>aburkavage</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>14:18:00</time><content>
 Crisp, on Broadway in Lakeview, counts the whole wing as 1 wing.  They're not the traditional buffalo-style wings, but I think they're the best in the area and the only place that actually fries them long enough! 
</content><char_count>216</char_count><word_count>40</word_count></reply><reply><id>6222571</id><author>beanbreath</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>15:53:00</time><content>
 I would think that most of the time you're going to get the individual sections rather than the jointed v.
And you all should be going to Tunes on Southport if you want to enjoy your wings. 
</content><char_count>193</char_count><word_count>38</word_count><reply><id>6223118</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>19:03:00</time><content>
 Toon's?  </content><char_count>11</char_count><word_count>4</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Real Omelets</title><id>6195391</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>15:38:00</time><content>
 I was served an "omelet" for breakfast in a pretty well known Chicago restaurant yesterday that was basically spinach and feta cheese mixed with eggs and poured into a pan.  The eggs were allowed to set and brown, then folded in half, put on a plate and served.  I have just learned that that style is called an "American omelet."  In my world, an omelet is the French-style omelet.  It is a work of art and a test of the skill of a chef.  It is yellow, fluffy and folded around fillings before it is plated and served.  Who serves real French omelets in Chicago? 
</content><char_count>567</char_count><word_count>113</word_count><reply><id>6195460</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>16:06:00</time><content>
 Just to clarify - it sounds like you're saying the main difference in styles is that in the so-called "American omelet" the extra ingredients are mixed with the eggs before cooking them, whereas in the "French-style omelet" they remain as a separate layer in the middle when the omelet is folded.  Is that correct? 
</content><char_count>318</char_count><word_count>57</word_count><reply><id>6195503</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>16:26:00</time><content>
 I didn't actually know that there were even different styles until I did some research on-line.  And there is not a lot of consensus about it.  The correct and accurate "main difference" is not what's important here.  I suspect that what I had was not even a conventional American Omelet, but what the kitchen could get away with.  It's just so often what passes for omelets and I'm frustrated because it's not what I want. 
</content><char_count>427</char_count><word_count>81</word_count><reply><id>6195517</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>16:35:00</time><content>
 I'm just trying to help, by understanding the distinction.  I've always liked the omelets at Walker Brothers, but it's been a while since I've ordered one there, so I'm not sure exactly which kind they serve.  What I remember most about them was that they are quite fluffy.  Another thought - I would expect the omelets at our French bistros to adhere the closest to the "authentic French style".  Have you tried them at the French bistros that are open for brunch?  Bistro Bordeaux in Evanston and Bistro Campagne in Lincoln Square both have omelets on their brunch menu.  (The current brunch menu at Bistro 110 only lists frittatas, in which all ingredients are usually mixed before cooking, and which are not usually folded over.)   Another possibility might be to order them at a buffet-style Sunday brunch where the chef makes omelets to order, and where you could ask them to make it exactly as you prefer.  The more upscale the brunch, the more they might be willing and able to accommodate your specific preference, so I'm thinking about places like NoMI and Seasons. 
</content><char_count>1079</char_count><word_count>195</word_count><reply><id>6195620</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>17:20:00</time><content>
 The omelets at Walker Brothers are not what I had in mind.  They are "fluffy" for sure, but that's because they are whipped just before the are cooked.  They sometimes seem to be too browned on the outside and  a little undercooked in the middle.  In fact, I find their egg white omelets to be like a half-cooked meringue and almost inedible   The omelets I'm referring to are more like these: </content><char_count>396</char_count><word_count>79</word_count><reply><id>6204756</id><author>dulcie54</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>11:21:00</time><content>
 I know exactly what you mean.  What passes for an omelet in American restaurants is an egg mixture that has been whipped and then cooked well past the point of tenderness.  It is probably made in response to the American desire for quantity over quality, since a true French omelet is a very delicate sort of thing.  In fact, if you read Elizabeth David's method for omelet making, it should cook for less than a minute and not be stuffed, just gently filled.  I have never had such a thing in a restaurant in America.  If you find one, let us know.  To my mind, this is the best sort of casual supper, a simple omelet with salad and good bread. 
</content><char_count>649</char_count><word_count>129</word_count><reply><id>6205014</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>12:42:00</time><content>
 Thank you.  I was beginning to think I was an "outlyer."  Many years ago I had an omelette aux fine herbes in an ordinary little neighborhood restaurant in Paris.  It rocked my world.  I had never tasted anything like it.  Now I don't expect anything like that, but I wish I knew where to get real deal here in Chicago.  I think I'm going to go buy a few dozen eggs and teach how to make it myself. 
</content><char_count>402</char_count><word_count>86</word_count><reply><id>6205219</id><author>jbw</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>13:45:00</time><content>
 "I think I'm going to go buy a few dozen eggs and teach how to make it myself."  That's probably a good solution, and Julia Child (Mastering the Art of French Cooking) is an excellent mentor for this. Other than for some good Greek omelets (filled with feta and spinach) I've had here and about, I've rarely had anything close to what I've had in France or could make for myself--up to the point where I've stopped ordering them. One exception might be </content><char_count>455</char_count><word_count>86</word_count><reply><id>6208450</id><author>solon</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>14:13:00</time><content>
 I watched a rerun of a TV episode of Julia and Jacques: Cooking at Home, where Jacques Pepin demonstrated the preparation of a proper French omelet.  You might be able to find it on YouTube? 
</content><char_count>194</char_count><word_count>38</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6209553</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>20:06:00</time><content>
 Many (many!) years ago when I lived in New York, I used to go to Mme Romaine de Lyon, a little east side spot that served ... omelettes, real french omelettes ... only omelettes ... you selected the primary ingedient you wanted as filling (many cheese options, many veg options,etc) and then the other items ... and they served you the most perfect omelette ever. The restaurant closed several years ago but there is a cookbook, The Art of Cooking Omelettes. I just checked Amazon and it seems to have become a collectors fave with *very* high prices but it's worth trying to get a copy from the library ... I miss them to this day. 
</content><char_count>636</char_count><word_count>118</word_count></reply><reply><id>6222060</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>12:57:00</time><content>
 This the spinach and cheese omelet I had, together with this thread started me on an odyssey.  I decided to find out how to make the perfect omelet.  I will tell you that it was a fool's quest.  There is no such thing  Here's what I learned: No one - not Julia Child - not anyone, really knows how to make the &quot;perfect&quot; omelet.  &quot;Rules&quot; I found included:  &#8226; The eggs should be lightly beaten
&#8226; The eggs should be well beaten to be sure there is no visible white
&#8226; The eggs should be whipped to a froth  &#8226; A good omelet has a small amount of water mixed in with the eggs
&#8226; A good omelet has a small amount of heavy cream mixed in with the eggs
&#8226; A good omelet contains nothing but eggs  &#8226; Salt should be mixed in with the eggs at the beginning
&#8226; Salt the omelet only after it is done  &#8226; The heat should be very high
&#8226; The heat should be very low
&#8226; The heat should start high and then be brought down to medium &#8211; or turned off all together.  &#8226; Omelets should be folded
&#8226; Omelets should be rolled  &#8226; The best omelet is made with two eggs on a six-inch skillet
&#8226; The best omelet is made with three eggs on a 10-inch skillet  If you're interested, I actually blogged about my experience at 
</content><char_count>1188</char_count><word_count>243</word_count><reply><id>6222573</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>15:53:00</time><content>
 This has been great fun to read.  One more tip, I bought an all-clad d5 9 inch omelette pan and it has turned me into a regular (and male) julia child with the eggs.  yes it was expensive, but there is no way to screw up an omelette in this wonder pan.  Oh, and to stay more true to a CH topic, the omelette at Cafe des Architechts in the sofitel watertower was great.  that was prior to the chef change, but they had terrific french styled breakfast items. 
</content><char_count>461</char_count><word_count>95</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Planned dining in Chicago</title><id>6214821</id><author>csb95</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>13:16:00</time><content>
 Hello!  I've been researching restaurants, etc for an upcoming Chicago trip at the end of March.  It will be by husband &amp; myself, arriving on a Wednesday pm and leaving Saturday afternoon. Of course there are far more places I want to try than we will have time for!  I have a plan for the most part, but had some questions.    Wed night: arriving around 5 pm. Our hotel (Amalfi on Kinzie in River North) has a complimentary drinks &amp; hors d'ouevres that we will probably take advantage of when we first get there.  After settling in I would like to go to </content><char_count>557</char_count><word_count>112</word_count><reply><id>6216042</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>21:59:00</time><content>
 First off, great choice of hotel - the Amalfi is wonderful. And their cocktail reception is as well - not like your standard hotel bad glass of wine deal, they serve great drinks and a full antipasto type spread. (When I moved to Chicago, the company I worked for put me up there initially and I was rather surprised when I stopped for a drink and was asked if Bombay Saphire was acceptable for my G&amp;T ... friends love the Amalfitini's as well). I might suggest you stroll up to Sable rather than going to Bin36 - it's just a few blocks and you could continue with good drinks and a great selection of small plates - as light or substantial as you find yourself wanting (and super deserts)  I'd also suggest a lunch or snack at </content><char_count>730</char_count><word_count>140</word_count><reply><id>6221884</id><author>csb95</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>12:07:00</time><content>
 Thanks for the help!  Gemini looks perfect, will definitely visit there if the timing works out.  </content><char_count>100</char_count><word_count>20</word_count><reply><id>6222222</id><author>lina14</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>13:47:00</time><content>
 Have lunch after your visit to the Museum of Science and Industry at </content><char_count>71</char_count><word_count>15</word_count></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Girl and the Goat w/o a rez - eating at the bar on a Saturday</title><id>6221777</id><author>njfreqflyer</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>11:37:00</time><content>
 I was unable to get a reservation at </content><char_count>39</char_count><word_count>10</word_count></post><post><title>Intelligentsia in Western Suburbs</title><id>6220247</id><author>GraceW</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>18:55:00</time><content>
 Where can I get a cup of Intelligentsia brewed coffee in the Western Suburbs? I had a cup of it at Labriola recently, and I thought it was the best, full-bodied coffee that I had ever had. I would like to have it again. I thought Whole Foods had it but they have Allegro coffee at their coffee bar.  Ideas? Thank you. 
</content><char_count>321</char_count><word_count>65</word_count><reply><id>6220468</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>20:31:00</time><content>
 They sell it in whole beans at many local Whole Foods stores, so you can brew it yourself.  If you're looking for coffeehouses where they brew it, have you tried contacting Intelligentsia to ask them?  You can find their contact info at </content><char_count>239</char_count><word_count>46</word_count></reply><reply><id>6220939</id><author>masha</author><date>2011-01-17</date><time>06:57:00</time><content>
 The coffee at Buzz Cafe in Oak Park used to be Intelligentsia.  Not sure if it still is as it's been awhile since I've been there.
</content><char_count>133</char_count><word_count>28</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Thoughts on Ria</title><id>6200350</id><author>drumwine</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>18:43:00</time><content>
 Hi Chicago Hounds....NY Hound here, will be in Chicago next month. Made a res. at Ria, and would like to get your thoughts on the place. Overall impressions, favorite dishes, etc.
TIA....
Drumwine 
</content><char_count>200</char_count><word_count>33</word_count><reply><id>6200414</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>19:12:00</time><content>
 I ate dinner there last month and it was a disaster, with numerous problems with the food as well as the service.  I described them at length in a detailed report in this topic:  Opinions of Ria please - </content><char_count>206</char_count><word_count>43</word_count><reply><id>6200681</id><author>drumwine</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>22:10:00</time><content>
 thanks nsxtasy....you've provided much food for thought (yeah..I went there). You encountered some of my restaurant pet peeves which will certainly factor into whether or not I keep this res. I was hoping to find the "next great thing" in Chicago....been to </content><char_count>260</char_count><word_count>44</word_count><reply><id>6200882</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>05:14:00</time><content>
 Given the recent reviews I've seen of Avenues, that would be my first choice.    At a visit to Everest a few months ago I encountered wonderful food, but gaffe after gaffe service-wise.  And other people have echoed my experience. Very disappointing for a restaurant that has been around as long as Everest.   Schwa is a unique experience.  If you can get a reservation it might be worth it.  I didn't love the food, but others have and I do want to go back to give it another try.  A recent poster here noted that they closed the night he had a reservation with no warning and no reason given.  Unless someone died, that's just weird, inappropriate, and bad business. 
</content><char_count>672</char_count><word_count>131</word_count></reply><reply><id>6201088</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>07:14:00</time><content>
 Your question about the "next great thing" covers a lot of ground, because some of the places you mention are expensive, chef-driven high-end places and others are mid-priced and more casual a la carte type places.  Not many truly high-end places open up in any given year.  Most of them have been around a a long time, especially Everest and Avenues (although it's only been a couple of years since Chef Duffy took over at the latter).  I don't think any place is worthy of that tag in the high-end group.  Among more casual restaurants, there are always many good ones.  (I ate at Boka last month and enjoyed it.)  There are always some that get lots of media buzz - of which the current leaders are the Girl and the Goat, and the Purple Pig - while others don't get the buzz but may be equally good.  For one of the latter, I love Sable, in the Hotel Palomar.  They've been open about a year.  They serve artisanal cocktails, and hired away their chief mixologist from the Violet Hour.  Chef Heather Terhune, who spent ten years in charge of Atwood Cafe, runs the kitchen, and the contemporary food is fantastic.  Don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee!  The "next great thing" will probably be Next, the new restaurant that Grant Achatz is involved in, but it's not open yet.  For places receiving the most buzz lately, check out Chicago Magazine's "hot list" at </content><char_count>1369</char_count><word_count>259</word_count><reply><id>6201318</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>08:46:00</time><content>
 I did just read (maybe in Zagat's weekly email) that Ria was just revamped, not major changes, but hopefully fixing the issues. 
</content><char_count>131</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6201565</id><author>drumwine</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>10:08:00</time><content>
 Thanks very much for the feedback &amp; ideas...will tuck into the thought bank.
nsxtasy...."next great thing" was offered as a 3-way pun on G. Achatz's project, my next potentially swoon-full meal, &amp; what's "hot" in your town. Was meant to cover a lot of ground.
And I love sweet corn creme brulee! Good call. If you're ever in NYC, Quality Meats has one of the best. 
</content><char_count>368</char_count><word_count>66</word_count></reply><reply><id>6201815</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>11:07:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; I did just read (maybe in Zagat's weekly email) that Ria was just revamped, not major changes, but hopefully fixing the issues.  What I heard is that the temporary closing for a couple of weeks is for a revamp of the interior and research on changes to the menu.  Unfortunately, neither of those were the problem areas we experienced in our ill-fated dinner.  OTOH I have heard that Ria heard about my post and took it to heart, so maybe they have made the changes needed.  So much of it was really basic stuff too, stuff that every restaurant should already know (like not trying to clear plates when people aren't done eating, like asking about coffee, etc). 
</content><char_count>667</char_count><word_count>125</word_count><reply><id>6218719</id><author>mountsac</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>08:17:00</time><content>
 Did Ria contact you regarding your post?  How did you know that your post had reached them?  I'm curious. 
</content><char_count>109</char_count><word_count>23</word_count><reply><id>6219178</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>11:41:00</time><content>
 I have not been in contact with them.  A friend went since then and was chatting with them, and they said they had heard the comments I posted. 
</content><char_count>147</char_count><word_count>31</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6211450</id><author>sommerw1</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>12:54:00</time><content>
 If you can get into Schwa its a must.  No, it is not impeccable service, the music is loud, they only play rap, and they are most likely stoned the entire time, but the food is as inventive and unpretentious as any fine dining in the city.  Had it not been for the 24 seats and lack of attentive staff it certainly would have received 2 stars on food merit alone.  Michael Carlson is tremendous and its BYO so you can save a couple hundred vs. the Trus and Avenues of the world. 
</content><char_count>482</char_count><word_count>98</word_count><reply><id>6211473</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>13:01:00</time><content>
 Beware, even if you get a reservation at Schwa, they may cancel it on you at the last minute.  See </content><char_count>101</char_count><word_count>23</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6208343</id><author>Chargenda</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>13:42:00</time><content>
 Nsxtasy has commented on how terrible the meal there was. I had the opposite experience and truly loved the whole experience. For me, the service is what set it aside, the perfect balance of high-end chic restaurant without too much pretentiousness.   I loved Ria and think it deserves that 2nd Michilen star it got!   I am always really really happy at </content><char_count>356</char_count><word_count>67</word_count><reply><id>6208508</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>14:28:00</time><content>
 My meal wasn't terrible, but it was FLAWED.  And the things that went wrong were things that shouldn't go wrong anywhere, not even at your neighborhood Chili's - trying to clear plates from diners who are still eating, failure to bring sweetener with iced tea, failure to ask if we wanted coffee service, failure to pour equal portions, undercooked food, tiny portions, etc.  This wasn't one or two things; problems occurred throughout the meal.  Most of those are likely due to improper training of the staff.  Maybe they have improved since last month, maybe they haven't.  But based on my dinner, it doesn't deserve one star, and doesn't even deserve a mention.  It was an absolute embarrassment for a restaurant that is supposed to be a high-end place.  I ate at Boka later the same week.  Now, let's keep in mind that Boka is not as high-end a place, nowhere near as expensive and not trying for the same somewhat formal dining experience.  But Boka really had its act together, with the servers, busstaff, and runners all doing their jobs flawlessly.  I even noticed a very impressive way the service staff dealt with one particular situation during the meal.  The contrast with Ria was like night and day. 
</content><char_count>1216</char_count><word_count>221</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6217916</id><author>DutchOenophile</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>18:20:00</time><content>
 My experience was also the opposite of nsxtasy.  I loved it.  International level quality; beautiful presentation, perfect execution.  I loved every bite and can't wait to return when they re-open soon.  IMHO better than Avenues and L20. 
</content><char_count>241</char_count><word_count>43</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Shopping on Argyle</title><id>6217671</id><author>beanbreath</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>16:00:00</time><content>
 We're thinking of heading out Monday for an early dinner after some grocery shopping.  I'm not really looking for anything too hard to get, I don't think--tree ear fungus, yuzu, kimchi, whatever.
Would you folks please recommend the best food shopping places around Argyle @ Broadway?
We're mostly looking for things to stack the larder and inspire us.  Thanks! 
</content><char_count>365</char_count><word_count>61</word_count><reply><id>6217912</id><author>Querencia</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>18:19:00</time><content>
 As you stand on Broadway across the street from the big Uptown Post Office, with your back to the street,  facing the strip mall, at your extreme left back in the corner there is an Asian supermarket that is loaded with inspiration. Then  walk north on Broadway, turn right on Argyle, continue on along Argyle to Sheridan, and turn right on Sheridan---following this route you will pass four or five other interesting food shopping venues. A good place for lunch is </content><char_count>468</char_count><word_count>85</word_count><reply><id>6218872</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>09:30:00</time><content>
 Also just to the north of that strip mall, same side, there is a smaller, sideways mall (jewelry on the corner? you'll see what I mean) with another asian market that's pretty big too.  Probably both carry the same goods.  Yeah, good route Q gives you.  Just stick your head into some of the shops.  Fun, quick day trip.  Stop at Tank or any of the other spots and get some pho while you're there.. 
</content><char_count>402</char_count><word_count>82</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Italian bread search - "ciopa</title><id>2920719</id><author>bubby</author><date>2007-09-07</date><time>14:01:00</time><content>
 I'm in search of a type of Italian bread my family once was able to purchase from local bakeris a few decades back on the south side/Roseland neighborhood.  Ciopa
Description: A type of crusty, thick bread from the Veneto.
Pronounced: CHYOH-pah (also 'cho-pee')
Language: Italian  The finished product has four or six tips or knobs. Somewhat similar to challah bread but smaller and less uniform - more bumpy/pointy. Anyone ever heard of this or know of any bakeries still making this today? 
</content><char_count>495</char_count><word_count>83</word_count><reply><id>2920812</id><author>kathinmadrid</author><date>2007-09-07</date><time>14:27:00</time><content>
 Ciapatta or also called ciabatta?  If you have a Spanish bakery around, the Spanish version is chapata.  Same thing and delicious. 
</content><char_count>134</char_count><word_count>25</word_count><reply><id>2920837</id><author>bubby</author><date>2007-09-07</date><time>14:38:00</time><content>
 Nope, I think it's different. My Italian uncle clearly pronounces it 'cho-pee'. 
</content><char_count>83</char_count><word_count>14</word_count><reply><id>4371536</id><author>Dianne22</author><date>2009-01-29</date><time>20:26:00</time><content>
 My husband grew up in Roseland and we go to Italy often.  I Chop-ee di pan is difficult to find even in the veneto today.  Chopee (I have no idea how to spell it properly and I lent out my italian food dictionary) is a pasta (dough) that is worked intensively by hand and it has a firm texture.  The bread your uncle probably remembers had  "cornetti"  pulled out bumps almost like large jacks we played with as kids.  I think there is a family bakery in wisconsin or you can actually go to Italy and there is one bakery near the Marco Polo airport in Venice That still does bread like that.  My husband has brought them back for his dad and buddies who all remember that special bread from Roseland. 
</content><char_count>704</char_count><word_count>141</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>2938309</id><author>amoncada</author><date>2007-09-13</date><time>11:25:00</time><content>
 D'Amato Bakery
1124 W Grand Ave
Chicago, IL   Naples Bakery
(708) 424-1810
3705 W 95th St
Evergreen Park, IL  Italian Bakery
82 E Lake St
Addison, IL
630.530.1605  Also try Cafe Da Luciano in Roselle. The Libreri family is wonderful. They bake their own breads and I'm sure they'll make you a batch if you call ahead. This place is really charming and full of born and bred Sicilians. 
</content><char_count>388</char_count><word_count>67</word_count><reply><id>2970937</id><author>fryrose</author><date>2007-09-24</date><time>11:31:00</time><content>
 I did a search for ciopa-my non-Italian family thought it was spelled chopee. I was referred to D'Amato's bakery and they had no idea what I was talking about. My family used to get ciopa at Torino's bakery on 115th Street in Roseland. I hope that is right-I asked my parents and it was long ago. I hope you find some. If you do, please report back. Now, if we could find rye bread like Slik's bakery used to have... 
</content><char_count>420</char_count><word_count>82</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>4362692</id><author>CJM Costante</author><date>2009-01-27</date><time>12:25:00</time><content>
 I'm on the great Italian Ciopette Hunt. Regardless of how it is spelled we're seeking the same nostalgic holy grail. I'll past a description I found on the net. I was calling the points of the bread 'elbow-like' but 'horns' is a more suitable description.   Italian - (followed by translation)
La Ciopa e il Ciopon
&#200; la &#8220;Ci&#242;pa&#8221; (con il &#8220;fratello maggiore&#8221; Ciop&#242;n) a rappresentare la tradizione panaria popolare dei vicentini. Si tratta di un tipico pane a pasta dura che in origine subiva il processo della doppia cottura (o cottura a secco), veniva cio&#232; cotto in forno e poi asciugato in biscottiera (da qui la definizione &#8220;pan ben coto&#8221;). 
La tradizione della doppia cottura, comune alle aree pi&#249; umide del Nord Italia, trae origine anche dall&#8217;esigenza di garantire al prodotto la maggiore commestibilit&#224; (non dimentichiamo che sino agli anni &#8217;40 anche il territorio vicentino era zona molto &#8220;umida&#8221;).
Oggi nel vicentino &#232; pi&#249; raro ritrovare la tradizione della doppia cottura, praticata abitualmente ancora solo in alcune zone dell&#8217;alto vicentino.
Qualcuno ricorda che nella tradizione popolare le &#8220;Ci&#242;pe&#8221; appena sfornate erano riposte in appositi cesti, poi appesi con cordicelle alle travi di legno del soffitto (&#8230;comunque lontano dalle &#8220;tentazioni&#8221; dei bambini) al fine di prolungarne quanto pi&#249; possibile la consumabilit&#224;. 
La Ci&#242;pa tradizionale aveva 4 o 6 &#8220;corni&#8221; e pesava circa 100 grammi.  The Chop and Ciopon 
It is the &quot;Chop&quot; (with the &quot;big brother&quot; Ciop&#242;n) to represent the tradition of popular Panaria Vicenza. This is a typical bread dough that lasts originally suffered the double process of cooking (or cooking dry), that was baked in the oven and then dried in biscottiera (hence the term &quot;pan well coto&quot;). 
The tradition of double cooking, common to most humid areas of northern Italy, also stems from the need to ensure the product more edibility (not forget that until the 40s the territory Vicenza area was very &quot;wet&quot;). 
Today in Vicenza is more rare to find the tradition of double cooking, yet usually only practiced in some parts of the Vicenza. 
Someone points out that in the tradition of the popular &quot;Chop&quot; just sfornate were placed in special baskets, then hung with cords to the wooden beams of the ceiling (... still far from the &quot;temptations&quot; of children) in order to extend as much as possible consumabilit&#224;. 
Chop had the traditional 4 or 6 &quot;horns&quot; and weighed about 100 grams.  THE GREAT CHIOPETTE HUNT CONTINUES!! 
</content><char_count>2454</char_count><word_count>405</word_count><reply><id>4719771</id><author>asartori</author><date>2009-05-27</date><time>14:27:00</time><content>
 I grew up in the same Roseland area and remember the bread as well. I have tried to make the (chopi) bread with no success. Has anyone found a recipe that comes close? Please share! 
</content><char_count>185</char_count><word_count>37</word_count><reply><id>4988521</id><author>keroseland</author><date>2009-08-29</date><time>10:58:00</time><content>
 I also grew up in the same Roseland area and remember the bread as well. I am also looking for a recipe - did you have any luck finding one? Please share! 
</content><char_count>158</char_count><word_count>34</word_count><reply><id>5065011</id><author>asartori</author><date>2009-09-28</date><time>15:17:00</time><content>
 No I havn't found a recipe yet, but I keep trying. I have a couple that I need to try. I'll keep you informed. Do you remember the name of the store where you used to get the Chopi? 
</content><char_count>185</char_count><word_count>41</word_count><reply><id>5099559</id><author>keroseland</author><date>2009-10-13</date><time>09:08:00</time><content>
 The name of the store is Del Santo's (not sure of the spelling) they moved to Calument City and then further south around Salk Trail. They stopped making chopa a long time ago. I cann't believe that It's so  hard to find the recipe - even with google. 
</content><char_count>255</char_count><word_count>51</word_count><reply><id>5111900</id><author>asartori</author><date>2009-10-18</date><time>07:17:00</time><content>
 I thought that was the name of the store. Thanks for the update. 
</content><char_count>68</char_count><word_count>15</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6182535</id><author>Hibiscus3</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>14:24:00</time><content>
 They are called cioppa or ciopa, and pronounced cho-pah. My mother-in-law made them regularly and froze them. They are very delicious and not too easy to make, but they are truly worth the work!!  She gave me the recipe and showed me how to make them.  I make them on occasion and freeze them.  One of my sons also makes them. He was living in Vicenza, Italy for a few years and looked up family there. The word, cioppa/ciopa means "tasty pieces of bread" in Italian, they told him in Italy. 
</content><char_count>495</char_count><word_count>96</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>5590729</id><author>nonna1</author><date>2010-05-03</date><time>19:48:00</time><content>
 My family is also originally from Roseland. I remember going to church at St. Anthony di Padua on 115th.St. and then my Dad would go across the street with Nonno to the bakery and buy the chiopette.for Sunday dinner.  I believe that it is a regional bread - only made in Veneto. (My family is from the provence of Vicenza.) I have never been able to find a source for this bread or even a recipe for it. None of my friends even know of it as their families are from different areas of Italy. So yes, the Chiopette hunt continues!! 
</content><char_count>534</char_count><word_count>104</word_count><reply><id>6181672</id><author>Hibiscus3</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>09:58:00</time><content>
 I have a recipe for cioppa/ciopa. My mother-in-law was born in Vicenza, Italy, and she made these all the time. They are hard Italian rolls that when rolled and shaped, have like horns. They are somewhat semi-difficult to make but so worth it! They are delicious. She gave me the recipe and showed me how to roll and shape them. I do make them and freeze them... 
</content><char_count>366</char_count><word_count>69</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>4362703</id><author>CJM Costante</author><date>2009-01-27</date><time>12:27:00</time><content>
 Forgot to mention, also contacted Gonella//Torino and they stopped making it when OSHIA wanted guards added to the chiopette making machine.  The baker couldn't get at the dough so they stopped making the bread. CJM 
</content><char_count>219</char_count><word_count>38</word_count><reply><id>5383806</id><author>mcunico</author><date>2010-02-07</date><time>10:53:00</time><content>
 Has anyone found were to purchase chopia?  There is nothing else quite like it. 
</content><char_count>83</char_count><word_count>17</word_count><reply><id>5686138</id><author>CJM Costante</author><date>2010-06-13</date><time>18:12:00</time><content>
 The above link is the result of my search for ciopa or ciopette. Making ciopa at home is a daunting task that many Veneti descendants have tried. It takes the skill and patience of a professional--I defer to Steve McKeever (nee Dodaro)--Piemonte Bakery in Rockford, Illinois. Buon Aguri a Tutti! 
</content><char_count>299</char_count><word_count>52</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>5686850</id><author>Culinaria</author><date>2010-06-14</date><time>06:22:00</time><content>
 I think the three locations posted by amoncada are on the money.  That or I'd head out NW to the Harlem/Irving area and go up and down Harlem between Lawrence all the way down to Fullerton.  Perhaps call and ask.  Loads of Italian bakeries and delis there. 
</content><char_count>260</char_count><word_count>52</word_count><reply><id>6040321</id><author>asartori</author><date>2010-11-05</date><time>14:20:00</time><content>
 I have some news that I hope some of you will like. I recently visited a Subway store to have a sandwich. I ordered with there Italian bread. While I was eating I had a Fourty Year Flash Back. This bread is Great, A lot like Chopi. I Purchased ten loafs of Frozen bread, for a buck a piece and took it home.Cut the 1 foot long  frozen dough into pieces and stacked them up to make some sort of pyramid. If you have any kind of shallow baking dish it helps to keep the pieces from moving around to much. Proofed it for 90 min. at 150degrees and baked for 15 to 17 min. at 350. I was totally shocked. I have found an easy way to get my CHOPI 
</content><char_count>643</char_count><word_count>134</word_count><reply><id>6217081</id><author>Hibiscus3</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>11:38:00</time><content>
 Excuse me, but this sounds awful! 
</content><char_count>37</char_count><word_count>8</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6182968</id><author>Hibiscus3</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>16:49:00</time><content>
 Know this type of rolls/bread. My mother-in-law was born in Vicenza, Italy. Her mother made/baked them, and she continued the tradition. She gave me the recipe and showed me how to make it. They are absolutely delicious, and time consuming, but worth the work. One of my sons also makes them. He lived in The Vicenza area and found our relatives there. The name/word "ciopa/cioppa" means tasty pieces of bread, according to the people from Vicenza. When I make them, I make a big batch and freeze them. They are shaped/formed and the "horns" develop as they "raise.". Hope this answers your question. They DO exist...... 
</content><char_count>624</char_count><word_count>108</word_count></reply><reply><id>6187172</id><author>Hibiscus3</author><date>2011-01-05</date><time>08:08:00</time><content>
 I have cioppa recipe and make it. It appears many are looking where to buy or to get recipe, but no one is responding. I guess you have lost interest...oh well! Will not post again... 
</content><char_count>187</char_count><word_count>37</word_count></reply><reply><id>6218804</id><author>dramisino</author><date>2011-01-16</date><time>08:59:00</time><content>
 One must go to Rockford to get real Cioppi (sp?)
There ARE safety rules that prohibit making in large bakeries. They are hand crafted. When I was a kid we would go nuts for it. 
</content><char_count>180</char_count><word_count>36</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Authentc northern Italian pizza on the Gold Coast</title><id>6193607</id><author>tlackner</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>06:09:00</time><content>
 We're looking for genuine ultrathin-crust pizza tonight, in the </content><char_count>66</char_count><word_count>11</word_count><reply><id>6193670</id><author>citywayne</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>06:36:00</time><content>
 A bit out of territory, but try Pat's in Lincoln Park on Lincoln Ave just north of Fullerton. 
</content><char_count>97</char_count><word_count>20</word_count></reply><reply><id>6194677</id><author>ms. mika</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>11:38:00</time><content>
 What about Pizzeria via Stato? I've only been once but it was good. See the link below to see if it's what you're looking for.
</content><char_count>129</char_count><word_count>26</word_count><reply><id>6196928</id><author>HoosierFoodie</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>10:05:00</time><content>
 This place came to mine, too.  I've had a pretty good (expensive) pizza at </content><char_count>77</char_count><word_count>17</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6196094</id><author>lwoerther</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>21:32:00</time><content>
 I haven't been to the new Sono Wood Fired, but I would imagine it's thin. Just off North, not too far. What about the thin at Pizano's? 
</content><char_count>139</char_count><word_count>29</word_count></reply><reply><id>6217493</id><author>Gfw</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>14:32:00</time><content>
 If it isn't too late...   Marios, really thin crust </content><char_count>54</char_count><word_count>13</word_count></reply></post><post><title>GABRIEL'S AND MIRAMAR IN HIGHWOOD</title><id>6217208</id><author>dlpens</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>12:30:00</time><content>
 On Friday night my wife and I had dinner at Gabriel's in Highwood where we have dined on numerous occasions.  Gabe met us at the door and our having known him for many years, we had a discussion first about his triumph in scaling Mt. Everest and then about his restaurant </content><char_count>274</char_count><word_count>54</word_count></post><post><title>Great Restaurants in Evanston, IL or Close By</title><id>6214103</id><author>kkumer</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:01:00</time><content>
 I'm looking for good somewhat upscale restaurants in or nearby Evanston, IL for a couples' dinner out....any ideas are welcome!!  Thanks. 
</content><char_count>141</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6214254</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:38:00</time><content>
 Evanston has quite an assortment of upscale restaurants.  Here are the best:  Oceanique - The most upscale restaurant in Evanston.  They emphasize seafood, but I've found that they also have some of the very best soups, sauces, and desserts you'll find anywhere.  Can be a bit pricy.  </content><char_count>287</char_count><word_count>54</word_count><reply><id>6214568</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>11:56:00</time><content>
 Evanston has some of the best restaurants on the North Shore.  Ditto on everything above EXCEPT Chef's Station and Stained Glass.    We were at Chef's Station a couple weeks ago for the first time in several years and remembered why we hadn't been there in a while. We were terribly disappointed. Service was fine and friendly. It was a Saturday night and we were one of only two tables there. One member of our party was served under-cooked fish. The rest of us were totally underwhelmed.  Prices were those I would expect for very good food downtown, but we didn't get that.  It was my recommendation to the other couple and I apologized after the fact. Sorry to say, but we would not ever return.  Stained Glass kind of falls into the same category for me.  The restaurant's promise and ambitions, IMO, far exceed what they deliver.  At least when I've eaten there. Wine flights are nice, but SG is also on our never-again list.  I'm interested in in how Pensiero is doing now that it has changed management.  Love to hear other people's experiences. 
</content><char_count>1057</char_count><word_count>198</word_count><reply><id>6214812</id><author>kkumer</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>13:14:00</time><content>
 Thank you - great suggestions, and appreciate the time you took to give detail.  Will avoid those two, but the others sound great! 
</content><char_count>134</char_count><word_count>26</word_count></reply><reply><id>6215096</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>14:37:00</time><content>
 I've eaten at Chef's Station numerous times over the years - maybe 2-3 times a year, with the most recent visit last month.  It has always been consistently excellent, including my latest visit.  It remains one of my two favorites in Evanston, along with the considerably more expensive Oceanique.  And that's based on lots and lots of visits (at least a dozen, maybe two), rather than a single isolated bad experience.  I hadn't been to the Stained Glass in quite a while until I ate there this past November.  There too, the food was very good.  I loved the foie gras BLT!  Again, though, it was quite crowded and noisy (it was a Saturday night).  As you can see, both of these were recent visits.  Also I should mention that I am not known as a "regular" in either place so I don't think I was getting any special treatment.  The problem with Pensiero is not the change in management before they re-opened in September; the problem is that the management has gone through a procession of head chefs, and are now on their fourth since re-opening.  Oceanique has always been excellent, and they often have specials that make it a bit less pricey than otherwise.  They are participating in the "Chicago Originals Restaurant Week" January 17 through February 6 and as part of this promotion will be featuring a four-course $29.11 menu, which is a great bargain for them.  You can see it at </content><char_count>1391</char_count><word_count>260</word_count><reply><id>6215246</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>15:25:00</time><content>
 nsxtasy, as you know we agree on many things, but we certainly have different experiences at some very specific restaurants.  While I know people, like you, who like one or the other, but I  stand by my experience. I would never recommend either Stained Glass or Chef's Station to a friend or relative.   With so many other good choices in Evanston, I suggest that kkumer choose something else.  Top of my list would be either </content><char_count>429</char_count><word_count>82</word_count><reply><id>6215272</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>15:32:00</time><content>
 Campagnola and Bistro Bordeaux are fine choices IF you're looking for Italian food or French bistro food, although Bistro Bordeaux can be quite noisy so it may not be best for a couples dinner.  For contemporary American cuisine (and the best food in Evanston), I'd put Oceanique at the top of the list. 
</content><char_count>307</char_count><word_count>56</word_count><reply><id>6217137</id><author>dlpens</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>12:05:00</time><content>
 For what it is worth, my wife and I have eaten at Stained Glass many times and we LOVE their food and service.  We always recommend it to friends and have never received one complaint. We have gone there with foodies and have hosted special dinners there and again, we have never heard one complaint about any course whatsoever.  And the numerous and excellent wine flights are a real treat.  I will not hesitate to recommend Stained Glass to anyone. And they offer excellent values with fix pris menus. Don 
</content><char_count>511</char_count><word_count>95</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>What's happening with "Next" restaurant</title><id>6216674</id><author>willyum</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>09:11:00</time><content>
 Any local 'hounds hearing any news about when this venture will open?  I'm on the mailing list but haven't received any updates ... was supposed to open late 2010, then I read in Time magazine maybe Feb 2011 ... you local guys hearing anything?  For those who don't know what "Next" is, it's </content><char_count>294</char_count><word_count>57</word_count><reply><id>6216729</id><author>hoppy2468</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>09:30:00</time><content>
 A post I saw on another food board was from a friend of someone working on the space. Opening date to be around 2/15 but this "worker" thought that was "very optimistic".
We all just have to wait. I'd tell you a secret I have on how to find out when they will open but then you would become one more person trying to get my reservation and that ain't gonna happen. :)
. 
</content><char_count>373</char_count><word_count>74</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Chicago Originals Restaurant Week - January 17-29, 2011</title><id>6216480</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>07:39:00</time><content>
 As in past years, there are two groups holding restaurant week events again this winter. The earlier one January 17-29 is held by Chicago Originals, a group of 16 independent restaurants in Chicago. Special dinner menus of 2-4 courses will be available for $29.11. For more information and menus, see </content><char_count>303</char_count><word_count>52</word_count></post><post><title>Chicago Restaurant Week - February 18-27, 2011</title><id>6216461</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>07:32:00</time><content>
 This is the big one, with over 200 restaurants participating. Prix fixe meals are $22 lunch, $33/$44 dinner. This year's participating restaurants are listed on the Chicago Convention and Tourism Bureau's website at </content><char_count>218</char_count><word_count>35</word_count></post><post><title>Unexpected long weekend in Chicago</title><id>6212828</id><author>meatn3</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>20:45:00</time><content>
 An unexpected opportunity to visit Chicago this weekend just came up! The majority of the time will be spent River North and The Loop. We'll have a few hours between meetings to explore, but will want to stay fairly close to the hotel (timewise).  Quick, casual meals look like Fox and Obel (room provisions too), </content><char_count>316</char_count><word_count>58</word_count><reply><id>6212886</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>21:15:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; We'll be staying North River around Michigan Ave. and Walton. Often my travel companion wants a quiet night in the hotel and just wants a pizza delivered. Hopefully this won't happen, but in the event it does I'd love to have suggestions for a great place that delivers to the area.  I don't know of a great place that delivers, but I would just walk over to Pizano's on State.  It's only about three blocks away.  You can phone ahead with your pizza order so it's ready when you get there, and you can either eat it there, or take it back to your hotel.  </content><char_count>561</char_count><word_count>112</word_count><reply><id>6212962</id><author>meatn3</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>22:48:00</time><content>
 Thanks for the correction - I think between my being rather verbally dyslexic and moving too fast it was inevitable!  Your suggestions look really on target. I'm very excited about my Sun. excursion - I think it will be difficult to decide what to order. The photo's look like a solo can dine easily at the counter?  </content><char_count>319</char_count><word_count>61</word_count><reply><id>6213258</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>05:58:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; I think it will be difficult to decide what to order. The photo's look like a solo can dine easily at the counter?  I've only eaten there for weekend dinner, when the bar has been occupied with people getting drinks while waiting to be seated.  At a less busy time, I'm sure they'll be happy to seat a solo wherever you want.  Also note that you can use the #66 Chicago Avenue CTA bus to get back to your hotel from Mexique, if you don't want to take a cab.  </content><char_count>464</char_count><word_count>97</word_count><reply><id>6213481</id><author>meatn3</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>07:17:00</time><content>
 Appreciate the extra helping! I'd rather spend on food than on transportation.  :-D 
</content><char_count>87</char_count><word_count>16</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6214256</id><author>HoosierFoodie</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:38:00</time><content>
 FYI, Malnati's delivers....  Or at least they did a few months ago. 
</content><char_count>71</char_count><word_count>15</word_count><reply><id>6214296</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:45:00</time><content>
 You're right; according to their website, the delivery zone for the River North location on Wells Street shows that Walton and Michigan is included.  It may take a little while, though.  If you order from there, ask for the pizza UNcut (i.e. not cut into slices) which will help it stay fresher while traveling. 
</content><char_count>315</char_count><word_count>58</word_count><reply><id>6215298</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>15:43:00</time><content>
 I order delivery from this malnati's all the time.  While nsxtasy may have an idea about ordering uncut, i never do and it always arrives piping hot and in perfect condition. Also, you'll be in a hotel without a proper knife. They put a wax type paper over the top (inside the box) that keeps it fresh and steamy.  Do be aware that delivery ranges from 1 hour to 1:15.    As a little treat, the cookie pizza also delivers well.  That all being said, the place is a pizza joint--you could wear sweats there (of course I don't) and not be under dressed. 
</content><char_count>555</char_count><word_count>111</word_count><reply><id>6215794</id><author>meatn3</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>19:12:00</time><content>
 Good point about no knife! I usually travel with some food tools, but we are just doing carry-on for the flight.   My friend and I traveled for work together for several years. I can't tell you how many wretched pizza's we had across the country on the nights she didn't want to leave the room! Now that I'm prepared years later she'll probably want to go out...
;-} 
</content><char_count>370</char_count><word_count>71</word_count><reply><id>6216446</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-15</date><time>07:26:00</time><content>
 I got the advice about getting pizza uncut from the folks at my local Malnati's.  It keeps the crust from getting soggy.  I can understand not being able to bring a knife in your carry-on (but you might borrow one from your own hotel).  Still, I think your best bet is to walk over to Pizano's, which is equally ultra-casual.  FWIW, both Pizano's and Lou Malnati's were founded by two sons of one of the main players in the first few decades of Uno and Due, and both sons spent many years working there before striking out on their own. 
</content><char_count>540</char_count><word_count>106</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6214360</id><author>meatn3</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>10:59:00</time><content>
 The website looks like they cover the area. I feel prepared if we stay in! Thanks! 
</content><char_count>86</char_count><word_count>18</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6213513</id><author>Chulacat</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>07:26:00</time><content>
 Give the Purple Pig a try.  It is on Michigan Ave near the Tribune building. 
</content><char_count>80</char_count><word_count>18</word_count><reply><id>6213544</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>07:36:00</time><content>
 Beware, Purple Pig doesn't accept reservations and waiting times for tables at dinner run 1-2 hours or more.  They serve the same menu all day long so lunch may be a better bet there. 
</content><char_count>187</char_count><word_count>37</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Reunion in Chicago</title><id>6215126</id><author>muybuena1029</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>14:47:00</time><content>
 I have 12 friends from college coming from in New York, San Francisco, Boston and Altanta for a reunion in Chicago in early April.  We are in our late 30's and leaving all the kids behind for a few days to catch up.  We are staying at the Palomar and are looking for some suggestions for the weekend.  1.  My husband and I would like to host something fun Friday night for everyone - perhaps drinks, a wine tasting, etc.  We will go out to dinner after so we were looking to do something to welcome everyone to Chicago - any suggestions  2.  We have a large group but want to find a restaurant where the atmosphere is conducive to conversation but the food still wonderful.  We would prefer to stay in the Mag. Mile, </content><char_count>719</char_count><word_count>145</word_count><reply><id>6215166</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>15:01:00</time><content>
 Some restaurants have one or more smallish private room(s) that would fit your group of 12.  Look for one of those.  Sable is right in your hotel and has a couple of small private rooms that would be perfect for your group.  The food at Sable is fantastic, contemporary American cuisine from Chef Heather Terhune.  Many dishes are available in half portion sizes as well as full sizes, so you can try more things.  Don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee!  Sable also features amazing artisanal cocktails.  </content><char_count>508</char_count><word_count>96</word_count></reply><reply><id>6216061</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>22:13:00</time><content>
 A drink reception at Sable in your hotel would be brilliant - they make amazing cocktails and the management is *very* cooperative and friendly so I bet they'd be happy to make a neat plan for you. As nsxtasy says, the food is also super and you could easily stay right where you are and have a great meal as well - they have a nice large table set off a touch from the main restaurant ...   If you'd like to go a bit pricier and more formal (Sable is surprisingly inexpensive for the quality and can be casual or not, depending on your mood) you might walk over to </content><char_count>568</char_count><word_count>114</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Casual Dinner In Northbrook Area</title><id>6203443</id><author>kwe730</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>21:45:00</time><content>
 A friend of mine that I have not seen in a long time is coming to town for business and I'm trying to think of a place that we can meet for dinner.  Looking for something casual with good food where the staff won't mind if we keep the pace slow so we can chat and catch up.  From reading the Chowhound board, the first place that comes to mind is Charlie Beinlich's, but wondered if anyone else had any other ideas.  Thanks! 
</content><char_count>428</char_count><word_count>88</word_count><reply><id>6203607</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>02:36:00</time><content>
</content><char_count>1</char_count><word_count>1</word_count></reply><reply><id>6204286</id><author>jjo</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>09:15:00</time><content>
 Check out Prairie Grass Cafe if you want something a bit above a are with good burgers, which is what Charlie Beinlich's is.  </content><char_count>128</char_count><word_count>26</word_count><reply><id>6205976</id><author>dlpens</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>18:17:00</time><content>
 You also have Blue Grass in Highland Park with wonderful dishes including cajun as the chef is from the south.  Very nice atmosphere.  And there is Next Door in Northbrook, next to Hole in the Wall with great Italian food although they both can get quite noisy.  My wife and I love Beinlich's  but remember that it is set up like a 1940's northern Wisconsin bar.  They still sell soft drinks from 2 liter bottles!  For Pan Asian there is Pacific Rim in Northbrook, which serves up Chinese, Korean, Thai and Japanese food.  The booths by the sushi bar are very comfortable and relaxing. Also consider J. Alexanders in Deerfield. Pick a cuisine and many more recs will appear. Don 
</content><char_count>682</char_count><word_count>129</word_count><reply><id>6206790</id><author>kwe730</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>06:05:00</time><content>
 Don, I appreciate the recs that you and the other posters gave me.  I'm definitely not interested in red sauce Italian, but open to most everything else. The location of the J. Alexanders would be great, but the last time I ate at one (in another city), everything I wore that night had to be sent to the cleaners because of a very poor ventilation system.  Casual is a big plus...as in nice jeans.
Thanks! 
</content><char_count>410</char_count><word_count>78</word_count></reply><reply><id>6207320</id><author>rjka</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:19:00</time><content>
 Abigail's Bistro in Ravinia is another option. 
</content><char_count>50</char_count><word_count>9</word_count><reply><id>6215245</id><author>dlpens</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>15:24:00</time><content>
 Abigail's Bistro in Ravinia is wonderful - but it can get very very noisy.  When we go there we try to get in very early before the bar fills up and the noise level increases. 
</content><char_count>179</char_count><word_count>38</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Saucisson Couenne</title><id>6201593</id><author>Karen1440</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>10:15:00</time><content>
 It's French, obviously.  Kate Hill says to ask for a cooked rind sausage.  Anybody have a clue where to get this, if possible, or can suggest a substitute?  This is for cassoulet which I have been making forever, but have not heard of this sausage. 
</content><char_count>252</char_count><word_count>50</word_count><reply><id>6215011</id><author>Karen1440</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>14:12:00</time><content>
 Never mind.  I shall use the sausages from D'Artagnan and not look further. 
</content><char_count>79</char_count><word_count>16</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Bridal shower location in Downtown Chicago - please help</title><id>6202920</id><author>kajol922</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>17:29:00</time><content>
 Hello!  I am looking for tips for where to hold a small bridal shower (15 ladies) in downtown Chicago.  I am trying to keep the cost as low as possible ($15-20/person).  Brunch on a Saturday is ideal, but will do tea, manicures, or another afternoon activity as well!  Thanks! 
</content><char_count>280</char_count><word_count>55</word_count><reply><id>6205104</id><author>lbs</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>13:08:00</time><content>
 Is this going to be a gift shower or a just a get together kind of a shower?  If with gifts, you may want to see if you can get a private room just for space and moving around.   Also, do you mean only dowtown Chicago or can you open up to the neighborhoods?  I think trying to find a place for $15-20 (especially if you are including drinks/cocktails) will be harder with downtown prices.  That being said, I'll suggest </content><char_count>423</char_count><word_count>87</word_count><reply><id>6205448</id><author>kajol922</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>14:56:00</time><content>
 Thanks for the reply - I do like </content><char_count>35</char_count><word_count>10</word_count></reply><reply><id>6213963</id><author>MollyChow</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>09:31:00</time><content>
 Yeah </content><char_count>7</char_count><word_count>3</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>So . . . what is the H Mart up to these days</title><id>6205911</id><author>onceadaylily</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>17:49:00</time><content>
 Sorry to be redundant, but I'm planning to visit H Mart within the next day or so, and the CH threads on this topic are a bit old, and things change.  I'd like a status update.  Yelpers just wants me to know that there is a lot of stuff, and that old Asian ladies are going to cart-bump me and cut in line.  I am most curious about the selection of fish.  I'll do the sniff test, but will I still be okay if I have a cold?  Is there a way to determine sustainability among the offerings (yeah, even I laughed at that, because if they have canned unagi, I'm buying).   Also, the fresh tofu?  I've heard it's worth having, but welcome second opinions.  If you have any favorites, or products that you've tried that were a disappointment, I would like to hear about them.  Thanks. 
</content><char_count>781</char_count><word_count>159</word_count><reply><id>6210240</id><author>tzurriz</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>07:04:00</time><content>
 Which H Mart?  There is more than one.  I was just at the Naperville store in December, and as always was impressed with the seafood department.  That day they didn't have a few things I was looking for, but they had easy substitutions.  For the live fish, the tanks were clean, which to me is a huge plus sign.  ;)  I only go a few times a year, but I've never been disappointed. 
</content><char_count>384</char_count><word_count>81</word_count><reply><id>6210323</id><author>onceadaylily</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>07:36:00</time><content>
 Sorry, I was referring to the one in Niles.  I've read some reviews that gave it very good marks, while others claimed that the smell of the fish was suspiciously pungent.  I didn't want to waste our time if it was the latter case.  But your report of the Naperville location is encouraging.  Thanks, tzurriz. 
</content><char_count>313</char_count><word_count>61</word_count><reply><id>6213037</id><author>citywayne</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>01:13:00</time><content>
 IMO (and my wifes) the tofu that is made fresh is excellent.   So is the soy bean milk.   The fish is typically very fresh (look at the eyes and gills as well as sniff testing).,   The selection is pretty good.   The pickled stuff is interesting (I'm not Korean).   I love going on the weekends and tasting the various items.   The sashimi is ok.   Most of the time just tuna, salmon, and fluke fresh.   Once in a while I have found yellowtail.    Their meats are a good value.   We get some of their ribeye steaks and slice meats for hotpots.
They are known for their cheap veggies.   People from Chinatown come up to the Niles store to shop in bulk.   The Korean specialties are usually fair to high priced.   Supply and demand I guess.   It's worth a visit, especially on a Saturday.   Go have lunch at their food court (small),.
Hope this helps 
</content><char_count>852</char_count><word_count>183</word_count><reply><id>6213267</id><author>onceadaylily</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>06:03:00</time><content>
 That does help, thank you.  Besides the fish, the tofu and kimchee were of particular interest.  And the boyfriend isn't supposed to have dairy, so fresh soy bean milk (the thought of which hadn't even entered my head) would be something we would both like.  I'm hopeful that they will have better-than-average selection for oils, sauces, and vinegars that are a bit harder to find in my area.  Thanks, citywayne. 
</content><char_count>417</char_count><word_count>76</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Restaurants that don't use MSG</title><id>6212729</id><author>clfleck</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>20:00:00</time><content>
 I will be in chicago in April to see a friend I haven't seen in 30 years. We'd like to treat them to a nice dinner. It doesn't have to be fancy but it MUST be MSG free as she is highly reactive. They live on a very low income and would not be comfortable with fussy or fancy but I want to treat them to a great experience. I'm not concerned with cost. We will be staying near miracle mile but I'm open to several areas. I think they live closer to o'hair. 
</content><char_count>459</char_count><word_count>96</word_count><reply><id>6212852</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>20:56:00</time><content>
 Any nice restaurant is happy to accommodate any food allergies, including MSG.  Actually, most of the nicer restaurants don't use it anyway, but it's always best to make sure - by mentioning it when making your reservation, and again telling your server when you are first seated.  There are many, many restaurants in Chicago that provide a great experience.  You'll need to narrow things down further - by type of food, by location, by any other criteria you'd like.  To help you do so, there are previous discussions that will provide good places to start, to help you get the "lay of the land".  This discussion tells what foods and places are unique or specialties in Chicago, foods that Chicago is particularly good at:  first time Chicago - </content><char_count>749</char_count><word_count>136</word_count><reply><id>6213218</id><author>clfleck</author><date>2011-01-14</date><time>05:37:00</time><content>
 Oops, my bad! Yes, Magnificent Mile!  Thanks for the help. I know MSG is just a hidden ingredient in so many things... It goes way beyond the old Chinese food issue. 
</content><char_count>169</char_count><word_count>34</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>One night in Chicago- where should we eat</title><id>6200083</id><author>StrongIsland</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>16:46:00</time><content>
 We will be in Chicago for one night in two weeks  What is a fun restaurant with great food? All ethnicities considered. I have always wanted to hit up frontera grille but wanted the opinions of locals. I believe we will be staying at the intercontinental hotel if that matters but will use cab for transportation. 
</content><char_count>317</char_count><word_count>59</word_count><reply><id>6200211</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>17:43:00</time><content>
 If you can get into Frontera do it, otherwise, it's hard to recommend one out of 2,000.  I guess it kind of depends what kind of mood you'll be in, in two weeks, how your day went, how many people, is it going to be snowing, are you going to a Hawks game after, kids, want to spend $200 per?  Et cetera.  Intercontinental is right in the middle, so that's good. 
</content><char_count>365</char_count><word_count>76</word_count></reply><reply><id>6200300</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>18:21:00</time><content>
 This discussion has recommendations describing places that are unique to Chicago and/or types of food that Chicago is particularly good at:  first time Chicago - </content><char_count>164</char_count><word_count>28</word_count><reply><id>6200331</id><author>caseyjo</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>18:33:00</time><content>
 I took my mom to Frontera for lunch when she last visited the city; we found that worked better than dinner (no wait). Like nsxtasy said, I would definitely recommend checking out Pilsen as well. That said, I wouldn't  consider Chicago to be a real Mecca for Mexican food (I'm originally from Southern California, so I'm picky). 
</content><char_count>332</char_count><word_count>60</word_count><reply><id>6200423</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>19:18:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; we found that worked better than dinner (no wait).  Only if you're lucky.  Usually there are extensive waits for lunch as well as for dinner.  &gt;&gt; I wouldn't consider Chicago to be a real Mecca for Mexican food (I'm originally from Southern California, so I'm picky).  I've eaten at most of the Mexican restaurants in Chicago, and I've eaten at many of the Mexican restaurants in Southern California.  There's no comparison - Chicago is far, FAR better for creative provincial Mexican food.  The Southland isn't bad - in fact, it's the only other part of the country that has at least a little variety in terms of provincial cuisine - but Chicago just has a lot more, and it's a lot better.  Much of the reason for that is Rick Bayless himself, who takes his staff to Mexico every year; many of his alumni have gone on to open Mexican restaurants around Chicagoland.  I wouldn't consider Southern California to be a mecca for Mexican food - it's a very distant second.  Try dining at Frontera Grill, Topolobampo, Salpicon, Mexique, Mundial Cocina Mestiza, Amelia's Grill, Mixteco Grill, Salsa 17, Yolo, Xni-Pec, Fuego, Don Diablo, Sabor Saveur, and Chilam Balam, and then see what you think.  (And that's quite aside from the conventional Mexican street food like you find at taquerias, etc.) 
</content><char_count>1298</char_count><word_count>233</word_count><reply><id>6200500</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>20:02:00</time><content>
 Oh, man (I don't know why we're talking about Mexican but ...) what's that place on Ashland, the seafood place?  The one a few blocks south of division?  I've only been there once but that place kicks assandro!  It would totally be worth a cab ride.  If it was summer I often recommend to touristas, man, drawing a blank, that place in Greektown with the rooftop?  Whatsitcalled? Not Santorini but right next door? Food's not that great but the view is six-flags!  Just suggesting, a day or two before you get here re-post with more details, what kind of food you're in the mood for, price, etc.  Beyond hot dogs and pizza, it's hard to give you a "Chicago dining" experience b/c there's such a variety.  Adios! 
</content><char_count>715</char_count><word_count>137</word_count><reply><id>6200801</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>01:55:00</time><content>
 The place on Ashland you're talking about </content><char_count>44</char_count><word_count>9</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6200557</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>20:30:00</time><content>
 I've eaten at Frontera and have not found it so hard to get a table - stop by about 20 minutes before they open and sign in for a table. They'll give you a time to come back - we've done that often and normally eaten around 6ish.  Another option is to head to Xoco for hot chocolate and churros as a great end to any evening.  That said, there are lots of other great places to eat. Some real favorites of mine are:   Mercat a la Planxa, one of Jose Garces' restaurants, in a great room overlooking the park and with a wonderful selection of super tasty tapas as well as great grilled items.   </content><char_count>596</char_count><word_count>123</word_count><reply><id>6201064</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>07:04:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; Sable - amazing cocktails and a varied interesting menu at all price points. (I never can get the link to come up for this but they're not far from your hotel at 505 N State)  Great rec.  I love the contemporary American food at Sable, and I don't even drink cocktails!  Heather Terhune, formerly of Atwood Cafe, is in charge of the kitchen.  Don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee!  Their website is at </content><char_count>409</char_count><word_count>82</word_count><reply><id>6203694</id><author>StrongIsland</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>05:07:00</time><content>
 Sable looks really interesting. Small plate concept always works for (love tapa). And they have some good cocktails. May be just the ticket for our dinner. Or maybe lunch. Or maybe just drinks. We only have one night so trying to make the most of it.   Ever heard of Chicago cut? Local friends want to go there. 
</content><char_count>315</char_count><word_count>61</word_count><reply><id>6203867</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>06:58:00</time><content>
 Chicago Cut is a recently-opened steakhouse in River North.  I haven't been there.  Frankly, for someone visiting from out of town, I wouldn't advise going to a steakhouse unless steaks are your favorite and anything else will not make you happy.  After all, if there is one type of food you can get in any city across the country, it's a good steak. 
</content><char_count>354</char_count><word_count>68</word_count><reply><id>6203966</id><author>lbs</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>07:38:00</time><content>
 I have to agree with Nsxtasy.  I have NOT eaten at Chicago Cut and my opinion is purely based on conjuncture.  But it looks like your everyday business dinner steakhouse.  Which is great if you are craving a steak and a martini.  Its location on the river will be a great asset during the warmer months but now in January, I would suggest going to any of the other resturants listed above. 
</content><char_count>393</char_count><word_count>78</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6207382</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:34:00</time><content>
 I have eaten at chicago cut.  Nothing special but a top-notch steakhouse.  Found the steaks to be very tasty (but so are everyone else's).  The wine list on the iPad was an interesting gimmick, but as an oenophile, i found it trite and hard to use.  The sides were good, but nothing extremely interesting.  The best thing it has going for it is the decor and service which were both excellent.  It's very open and airy and has nice views.  Crains just reviewed them as a great power-breakfast place by the way.    That all being said, my two favorite steaks are at Joe's (then you can get crab claws to make it a surf and turf) and my second favorite is Keefer's (again after years).  Keefer's adds terrific sides and a real non-steak menu for those not into beef. 
</content><char_count>768</char_count><word_count>152</word_count><reply><id>6212518</id><author>StrongIsland</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>18:43:00</time><content>
 I hear you on the steakhouse. Wasn't my call. I only do steakhouses for business dinners. And that's plenty.   What about table 52? 
</content><char_count>135</char_count><word_count>27</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Foodie needs recs on cocktails and brunch</title><id>2228934</id><author>gastronomicalme</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>06:49:00</time><content>
 Will be in Chicago for 3 days and want to know what's new on the cocktail scene. Is there anywhere doing drinks to the level of Audrey Saunders at the Pegu in NYC? Also, need a new brunch recommendation. I have been to the Bongo Room several times and find it to be ok and am looking for somewhere else. I own a wine shop in Boston and am curoius how  Juicy wine bar is? 
</content><char_count>374</char_count><word_count>78</word_count><reply><id>2229217</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>08:06:00</time><content>
 There are tons of places all over Chicago to do brunch.  Asking where to do brunch, without specifying a location or any other qualifier, is like asking where you can find a nice dinner.  There are literally hundreds of places where you can find a nice brunch, in the city and suburbs.  Places in the city that are known specifically for their brunch (like the Bongo Room is in Wicker Park and the South Loop) include: Kitsch'n in Roscoe Village and in River North; Orange in Lakeview and the South Loop; Wishbone in the West Loop and on N Lincoln; Flo in Wicker Park; and M. Henry in Andersonville.  Most of them are busy for brunch, with long wait times.  Fine dining restaurants in the city that serve brunch on Saturday and/or Sunday include NoMi, Seasons, Frontera Grill, and North Pond.  The Ritz-Carlton recently stopped serving in the Dining Room, but they are continuing their highly-regarded Sunday brunch in their Cafe.  I haven't been to the Sunday brunch at the Signature Room at the 95th, at the top of the John Hancock Building; their food is not generally all that highly regarded, but on a clear day, you can't beat the view.  In the northern suburbs, Walker Brothers is known for their stained glass and their huge baked apple pancake.  And these answers just scratch the surface.  Metromix is the entertainment website of the Chicago Tribune.  Their guide to articles on brunch places is at </content><char_count>1412</char_count><word_count>258</word_count><reply><id>2230113</id><author>gastronomicalme</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>11:16:00</time><content>
 thanks for through response-very helpful. 
</content><char_count>45</char_count><word_count>7</word_count></reply><reply><id>2286714</id><author>DanielVest</author><date>2007-02-12</date><time>19:38:00</time><content>
 The M Henry page is hiding on about page 6 of a Google search.  Here is the link </content><char_count>83</char_count><word_count>21</word_count></reply><reply><id>2999564</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-10-03</date><time>07:35:00</time><content>
 I ate brunch at Bongo Room yesterday, and was delighted as usual.  I always enjoy eating breakfast/brunch at *all* these places, especially ones I haven't been to in a while.  What I like about the breakfast menu is that I can get sweeter items (pancakes, French toast) when I'm in the mood for that, and savory items (eggs/omelets, bacon) when I'm in the mood for that.  One thing I love about Bongo Room is that they can do a split order for you - IOW, even though their pancakes and French toast normally consist of three pieces, you can order a smaller portion size of one or two pieces at a reduced charge.  That way you can try more than one menu item.  Yesterday I was in a mood for sweeter items, so I had a blueberry cheesecake pancake topped with almond panna cotta cream - that was HEAVENLY - and the strawberry-mango brioche French toast, which was very good, too.  And during the week, there are no concerns about long lines.  Incidentally, for whatever reason, Bongo Room's website is down right now, but you can see their menu at </content><char_count>1047</char_count><word_count>199</word_count></reply><reply><id>5365259</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-01-31</date><time>13:02:00</time><content>
 Orange now has a website at </content><char_count>30</char_count><word_count>8</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2230401</id><author>ljero</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>12:20:00</time><content>
 for brunch, I have two recommendations.  For a Sat brunch, go and try Frontera Grill; all of his best lunch items are on there, plus some huevos rancheros, etc.  for a Sunday burnch, travel to Sweets &amp; Savories on Fullerton. It is nicer than others and reaosnable. three courses for $16, includes: coffee/tea and homemade pastries, appetizer two to choose by the week, entree (have to try the duck hash and the bacon breakfast egg risotto) and get a side of bacon.  It also includes one cocktail and they make a mean mimosa and even better, sometimes, if you're lucky, a bellini with fresh pureed mango or some other exotic fruit. 
</content><char_count>634</char_count><word_count>116</word_count></reply><reply><id>2230439</id><author>swsidejim</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>12:28:00</time><content>
 I enjoyed brunch @ Salpicon, one of the better Mexican restaurants in the city.  great food great choices of tequila  Salpicon 
1252 N. Wells
Chicago, IL.  </content><char_count>158</char_count><word_count>30</word_count></reply><reply><id>2231845</id><author>Beatnik</author><date>2007-01-26</date><time>18:42:00</time><content>
 Hey everyone, new to the board.  My new favorite Brunch is at Sola, Byron &amp; Lincoln in NorthCenter/Lincoln Square.  Reasonably priced, fun menu, absolutely delicious.  Look forward to posting much more! 
</content><char_count>206</char_count><word_count>36</word_count><reply><id>2258741</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-02-04</date><time>11:19:00</time><content>
 I had brunch at Sola this morning, and I thought it was very good in all respects - food, atmosphere, and service.  The Sunday brunch menu was very similar to the one on their website.  Additional note number 1 - no long waits.  Granted, this was a frigid morning.  However, it is a good-sized place and I doubt that they ever get long waits.  Furthermore, Sola takes brunch reservations, and you can make reservations there on opentable.com which lets you see what time(s) they have available.  All easy as pie.  Additional note number 2 - The street address of the restaurant is 3868 N. Lincoln, but don't look for it on Lincoln or you'll drive right past it.  The restaurant entrance (as well as all of its visibility) is on Byron, the side street.  sola restaurant
3868 N. Lincoln Ave. @ Byron
Chicago. IL 60613
(773) 327-3868
</content><char_count>833</char_count><word_count>154</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2236707</id><author>ems</author><date>2007-01-28</date><time>19:40:00</time><content>
 I have not found any place in Chicago that does cocktails at the level Pegu in NYC.  If anyone knows of a place like that in Chicago PLEASE say so. 
</content><char_count>151</char_count><word_count>33</word_count></reply><reply><id>2242132</id><author>TonyC</author><date>2007-01-30</date><time>11:32:00</time><content>
 Juicy Wine bar was a blast  We had a butter plate coupled with Red Hen's whole wheat honey loaf and drank some fun/cheap/unrespected moscato (i was w/ a buncha eono nooobs so...). Linda, our tender, was clearly a foodie and didn't flinch when i pulled out my Canon to take a pix of the "butter flight".  The whole downstairs space smelled of rochefort cheese. I also saw a unique bubbly sake on the shelf which i have yet to see at Mitsuwa/H-mart. In fact, thanks for reminding me, i'm off to pick up that bottle right now for tonite's kaiseki.   The wine list isn't thorough as some other new-on-the-scene winebars, but it also doubles as a retail store so any wine you can order off the list can be purchased for home consumption.   As far as brunch locales, nix half of the nsxtacy's (btw, are you an Acura driver?) profferings. Bongo / Wishbone / Twisted Spoke / Flo / Kitsch are all completely played out. Long lines, blah blah food (or in Flo's case, overly creative food, with a chef that has zilch palate).  Want quaint high quality brunch? Try an alternative like Yoshi's on Halsted. Biggest freakin' crab cake benedict you'll ever see in the Midwest.  Want haute brunch? Hit up the unrushed Custom House on Sunday and ask if you can see the pastry/cheese/dessert plate for dinner. They'll most likely obliged and you'll end up with a glorious (the entire restaurant is flooded with sunlight) 2 hour, 3-course brunch. It doesn't hurt the place is helmed by a James Beard award winner. IMO, it's also the "better" of all of Shawn M's restaurants.  Want hip S. American inflected brunches, try Bravo on Division, Cuatro on State (? I think it's on state). Nothing like starting off a morning with a pitcher of sangria.   I'd also second (and third, and fourth) the Sweets and Savories rec. By far the best "proper" brunch value in the city, dollar for dollar, ounce for ounce. Just stop spreading it around. It's hard enough to get a table as is. We just had our engagement brunch there last weekend, everyone had a blast. the food, from the hand made scones to the loved-by-ladies palmier, was impeccable. W/o the old efficient service staff, we were entertaining ourselves in between entrees, but it mattered not. 
</content><char_count>2226</char_count><word_count>403</word_count><reply><id>4068634</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-09-28</date><time>19:09:00</time><content>
 Custom House no longer serves Sunday brunch. 
</content><char_count>48</char_count><word_count>9</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2440015</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-04-01</date><time>07:53:00</time><content>
 I should add Lou Mitchell's to the above list.  Lou Mitchell's has been around since 1923, and is much more of a traditional breakfast place - think of a busy lunch counter where they're slinging hash and eggs and hurried businessmen (and businesswomen) stop there every day for a coffee and this is the place you're thinking of.  They're just west of the Loop, near the commuter train stations (no coincidence), and they're open seven days.  Lou Mitchell's Restaurant
565 W Jackson Blvd
Chicago, 60661
(312) 939-3111
</content><char_count>520</char_count><word_count>88</word_count></reply><reply><id>2517300</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-04-26</date><time>09:37:00</time><content>
 Today's Chicago Tribune has several articles on weekend brunches.  It includes the following articles (subscription may be required for Internet access):  "The ultimate brunch guide" (with reports grouped by brunches with music, with views, with a family vibe, with fabulous French toast, with a laid-back pace, and elegant and tranquil):
</content><char_count>341</char_count><word_count>53</word_count></reply><reply><id>2518029</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2007-04-26</date><time>12:27:00</time><content>
 Curious, what is the level of cocktail at Pegu?  I used to live in the Village until 2000 and was never terribly impressed with any of the $10+ cocktails I bought in NYC.  Granted, mixology was not popular until recently.        There are quite a few interesting places here in Chicago.  My favorite is Nacional 27--the bartender, Adam Seger is great and goes so far as to even make his own bitters.  There will always be something new he's succesfully mixing, but homemade bitters in the classic old-fashioned is a great way to start any evening.  The restaurant is also great, nueavo-latino, and begins to morph to a SoBe-type latin lounge around 10 on weekends.  IT's owned by a huge restaurant corp, but don't let that stop you--the chefs for each LEYE restaurant are also owners (like the Chodorow empire).  </content><char_count>815</char_count><word_count>155</word_count></reply><reply><id>2838260</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2007-08-12</date><time>12:36:00</time><content>
 We went out for brunch today around noon.  We decided to drive past M. Henry to see if they had the usual crowds waiting outside - they did - and we then went to Magnolia Cafe in Uptown.  We were seated inside immediately (even though their lovely outdoor sidewalk dining area was rendered undesirable by the current spell of heat and humidity).  We had the "Smoked trout hash with caramelized onions, roasted red peppers, applewood smoked bacon and hollandaise sauce.  Served with two eggs any style" (we chose poached) and the "Crab Cakes and poached eggs over English muffins, roasted red peppers and old bay hollandaise.  Served with house Potatoes" (mashed).  Both dishes were excellent, with a bit of spice to them.  Our accompanying bloody mary and fresh-squeezed orange juice were fine too.  This was an all-around great place for a laid-back neighborhood type brunch.  Highly recommended.  </content><char_count>901</char_count><word_count>159</word_count></reply><reply><id>3429960</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-02-24</date><time>12:00:00</time><content>
 Today we went for the first time to Between in Wicker Park for Sunday brunch, and it was superb; we loved it.  Walk in, and you immediately notice that the atmosphere is comfortable/cozy; I can see why their website refers to it as a "boutique cafe and lounge".  There's a long bar along one side of the room, with thickly-upholstered bar stool type seats with backs.  There are three kinds of tables: high two-tops with the same seats at them as at the bar; conventional-height four-tops with conventional chairs with matching thick upholstery; and huge overstuffed couches with low tables (like wide coffee tables) in front of them, some of which are behind a thin curtain-like arrangement.  Comfy and nice, wherever you are.  We chose Between because the brunch menu on their website (at </content><char_count>793</char_count><word_count>141</word_count><reply><id>3430347</id><author>ShikaSfrn</author><date>2008-02-24</date><time>14:35:00</time><content>
 I think Orange and Flo are pretty overhyped and not too special in my opinion.  I do second the recs on Bongo Room (even though still very hyped), M. Henry (very hyped), Sweets and Savories, and Magnolia Cafe.    I would also add Lula Cafe, which is in the west part on Kedzie.  They change their brunch menu every weekend and are known for their creative brunch menu, using local and seasonal ingredients.  I've always really really enjoyed brunch there, and have yet to be let down.  It's also very reasonable, and I love the crowd and atmosphere.  Whatever you do, report and let us know how it went! 
</content><char_count>607</char_count><word_count>118</word_count><reply><id>3430470</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-02-24</date><time>15:19:00</time><content>
 I went to Lula, in Logan Square, for brunch last year; I just hadn't posted about it.  I enjoyed it.  They have a nice-sized al fresco seating area on their front sidewalk, which made it very pleasant.  (Of course, that enjoyability is weather-dependent, not suitable for February; similarly, Magnolia Cafe has a few tables on their front sidewalk, but the day I ate brunch there in August was too hot to do so comfortably.)  At Lula, I had one of their pancake specialties with mascarpone and fresh fruit and it was very good.  Their menu tends to lean a bit towards the country/hearty and a bit more of a seasonal/organic and vegetarian emphasis, in case that appeals to you.  I went around the time they opened, and was seated immediately, but if I recall correctly, a few people were waiting to be seated by the time I left.  Lula serves a conventional breakfast menu during the week; on weekends, they offer more creative brunch specialties.  Thus they are one of the few restaurants (along with Sola in North Center, and Prairie Grass Cafe in Northbrook) where you can go for a nice brunch menu on a Saturday as well as a Sunday.  (Frontera Grill has brunch on Saturday but not Sunday.)  </content><char_count>1196</char_count><word_count>223</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>3431172</id><author>gundy1814</author><date>2008-02-24</date><time>20:16:00</time><content>
 In addition to all of the great recommendations, I also really enjoyed Tweet for brunch (</content><char_count>91</char_count><word_count>17</word_count></reply><reply><id>3434160</id><author>delk</author><date>2008-02-25</date><time>16:33:00</time><content>
 For cocktails, try </content><char_count>21</char_count><word_count>5</word_count><reply><id>3437339</id><author>msilverman</author><date>2008-02-26</date><time>13:39:00</time><content>
 I would definitely recommend The Violet Hour for both classic and inventive cocktails, in line with Pegu. The decor is beautiful, the lighting dim, and the cocktails delicious. It can get crowded and they often won't let a larger party sit at tables without purchasing carafes of cocktails. 
</content><char_count>294</char_count><word_count>50</word_count><reply><id>4292136</id><author>sleeper65</author><date>2009-01-03</date><time>07:51:00</time><content>
 I also think the Violet Hour is great...a little tough to find.  It looked boarded up and only had a yellow light above the door and the Home Depot adhesive style address #s (1520).  We had to ask in another shop to find it and another customer explained where it was and even caught us later on the street to correct his directions to us!  (Chicagoans are so helpful!)  Anyway, the drinks were fun (I had a sidecar which is what I like to make at home) and it was very good.  We had the deep fried pearl onions and they were interesting...not fabulous, but good.  We've already been recommending this place to friends.  We went on a Tuesday at about 6, so we walked right in, but it started filling up right after that.  I'm a CH newbie, so thanks for turning me on to this place! 
</content><char_count>785</char_count><word_count>158</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>3543326</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-03-30</date><time>12:53:00</time><content>
 I went to brunch at the Wicker Park location of Toast for Sunday brunch this afternoon, and it was quite good.  They have a variety of breakfast and lunch items on their menu.  I had the stuffed French toast - two pieces stuffed with mascarpone cream and one with chocolate pastry cream (they have each on the menu, and were happy to prepare the combination when I asked) - surrounded by a nice-sized portion of fresh strawberries, blackberries, blueberries, and grapes.  Also fresh OJ.  All very good.  I arrived at 1 p.m. and was done around 1:30.  As a solo, I was able to be seated at one of the half dozen seats at the counter immediately.  Throughout that time, there were 8-10 people waiting at the entrance.  It's not huge, but big enough that the wait wouldn't have been all that long for those waiting for tables.  Toast
2046 N Damen Ave
(773) 772-5600
</content><char_count>865</char_count><word_count>163</word_count></reply><reply><id>4130495</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-10-26</date><time>17:20:00</time><content>
 Today I ate the "American dim sum brunch" at David Burke's Primehouse in the James Hotel.  Bottom line, I thought it was excellent.  There were also some noteworthy differences from what I was expecting (and, in general, they were for the better).  When I was seated, I was presented with the American dim sum menu.  I had noticed that an a la carte breakfast menu was posted alongside the dim sum menu at the entrance, and asked whether both were available, and was told that they were, and was asked whether I would like to see the a la carte menu; I declined.  The menu was similar, but not identical, to the one on the BRGuest website ( </content><char_count>643</char_count><word_count>125</word_count><reply><id>4159818</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-11-09</date><time>10:12:00</time><content>
 When I went to Burke's, I also happened to be walking through the Peninsula Hotel nearby. I checked out the buffet brunch being served at the Lobby restaurant. It looked very nice indeed. I just called them to ask how much it costs, and they said $62 per person. Just so you know that is not a typo - $62 (sixty-two dollars) per person. I think that's probably the highest price of any brunch in Chicago, aside from maybe a specially-priced special occasion holiday brunch. I know NoMI (in the Park Hyatt) is $55, and my recollection of the last time I went to Seasons (in the Four Seasons) a couple of years ago is that it was $50, although it could have gone up since then. The Signature Room is $42, and I don't know if the food is comparable, but that includes the best view in the city.  By comparison, David Burke's Primehouse is a bargain at $35 (and even more so for the unlimited alcohol for $10). 
</content><char_count>910</char_count><word_count>173</word_count><reply><id>4437511</id><author>lindygal</author><date>2009-02-20</date><time>17:01:00</time><content>
 Yeah, the Peninsula folks still think they're in Hong Kong before the handover.  Nobody here spends that much on brunch unless it's on an expense account or they don't know where else to eat.  I don't doubt it's tasty at the Peninsula, but for that price you could walk a few blocks north and get as good a brunch for less at Seasons at the Four Seasons in the Bloomie's building.  That said, Walker Brothers and Lou Mitchell's are the local standards for best brunch at the best price -- but Chuck's Southern Comforts Cafe on 95th in Burbank comes very close in price and is their equal in quality; besides, Chuck's brunch is New Orleans style, complete with coffee and chicory, Eggs Benedict and variations, and Bananas Foster French toast.  Yummy!! 
</content><char_count>755</char_count><word_count>138</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>4150501</id><author>uhockey</author><date>2008-11-05</date><time>02:35:00</time><content>
 Does anyone know if M Henry does the breakfast bread pudding during the week, or if that is a weekend-brunch specific? 
</content><char_count>122</char_count><word_count>23</word_count><reply><id>4150504</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-11-05</date><time>02:48:00</time><content>
 On their website ( </content><char_count>21</char_count><word_count>6</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>4227405</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2008-12-07</date><time>12:58:00</time><content>
 Here are reports on Sunday brunch at Big Jones in Andersonville, and Hot Chocolate in Wicker Park.  Today we went to Big Jones, which is on Clark Street across the street from Swedish Bakery (unfortunately, the bakery is closed on Sundays). They bill their food as &quot;Coastal Southern Cuisine&quot;, which is a good description, since it includes cajun and creole items you might find in Louisiana, as well as more typical southern items like grits and sweet tea (3 kinds!) that you might find across the south. One of the nice things about Big Jones is that they accept reservations (including through Opentable) so you don't have to worry about the possibility of a long wait to be seated (although during the 12:00-1:30 time we were there, no one was waiting).  When we were seated (at one of the two window tables - yay!), we were brought some excellent complimentary beignets. In addition to sweet tea, we had cafe au lait, which was served in an enormous coffee cup. We started with the fried green tomatos, which were superb, the best I've ever had. They were very hot out of the fryer, the breading (which I think contained some corn meal) was superb, and they were topped with chunks of shrimp and an excellent remoulade sauce. Yum!  We then had two savory dishes and a sweet one: (a) &quot;Eggs New Orleans - Lump crab cakes on fresh popovers with poached eggs, b&#233;arnaise sauce, and potatoes O'Brien&quot;; (b) Eggs Romero - Poached eggs, pulled pork in a tangy barbecue sauce, served over a bed of grits (I know it says potatos on the website menu, but the actual menu said grits, which is how they were served); and (c) Whole Wheat Banana Almond Pancakes. All three items were very good. Of particular note was the gigantic size of the three pancakes.  Service was good and friendly, and the decor is understated contemporary in a typical narrow but somewhat deep storefront. All in all, an excellent choice for brunch! Especially worth considering as an alternative to long waiting times at M. Henry, which is half a mile north of Big Jones on Clark Street.  Big Jones
5347 N Clark St.
Chicago IL 60640
773-275-5725
</content><char_count>2114</char_count><word_count>375</word_count></reply><reply><id>4238279</id><author>bonnie_ vivant</author><date>2008-12-11</date><time>06:58:00</time><content>
 Was just in Chicago on business in November - went to event at
 Drawing Room at Le Passage, 937 N. Rush Street -  - Dinner was  Lemon risotto with mascarpone, meyer lemon and lavender gremolata or Skate with sauteed skate wing, baby arugala, roasted sunchoke, sultanas and caper emulsion or Verjus braised pork belly, shaved spicy pecans, smoked eggplant puree and apricot.  They also have high end drinks with award winning  master mixologists. 
</content><char_count>449</char_count><word_count>79</word_count></reply><reply><id>5365282</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-01-31</date><time>13:09:00</time><content>
 Today we had brunch at Perennial, in Lincoln Park.  Everything was really wonderful!  This is an a la carte brunch.  The dishes are slightly smaller than some other brunch places, but the prices are quite low, so it's still a decent value.  (The most expensive dish on the menu is their $12 burger.)  What's nice about having smallish dishes is that it lets you try more than just one dish, and there are many delicious things to choose from.  We started with their breakfast croquettes, seven of them each the size of a ping pong ball, made of eggs, potato, and sausage, ground up with a creamy inside and a nice crusty outside.  We then had two main dishes.  One was the short rib hash, a superb rendition indeed; lots of short rib flavor, only a little bit of added potato and onion, over a brioche crouton the size of a burger, sitting on top of an outstanding reduction and sopping it up, with a fried egg on top.  The other was the duck confit tart, which was very good if a bit overly small, but the poached egg and frisee accompaniments were nice.  We finished with their French toast, which was exceptional, made from an almond baguette, nicely soft and moist, topped with diced apples and lemon ginger creme fraiche.  You could easily get by with only three dishes rather than four, but we wanted to try all of these items.  </content><char_count>1337</char_count><word_count>256</word_count></reply><reply><id>5386670</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-02-08</date><time>12:49:00</time><content>
 Yesterday I had Sunday brunch at Cafe 28 in Ravenswood.  It was very good!  The menu at Cafe 28 features a combination of dishes: Cuban, Mexican, and American.  It's quite a large place, which you wouldn't necessarily know from passing by on Irving.  I had made a last-minute reservation on Opentable.com, just to play it safe, but it turns out there were some empty tables the entire time we were there.  We had the crab cake benedict and the asparagus and Serrano (ham) benedict; both were very good, with a spicy hollandaise sauce.  The crab cake was nice and crabby, and spicy on its own, too.  Very enjoyable.  Cafe 28 serves brunch on Saturdays 10-2 and Sundays 9-2.  Cafe 28
1800 w irving park rd
chicago, il 60613
773 528-2883
</content><char_count>737</char_count><word_count>137</word_count></reply><reply><id>5505170</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-03-27</date><time>11:16:00</time><content>
 Earlier today I had brunch at Jam in West Town and I thought it was excellent.  Jam just opened within the past year, and has gotten a lot of favorable press.  It's small (although I think I noticed additional space outside for outdoor seating in warmer weather), with contemporary decor and a young eager waitstaff that combine to give it a trendy vibe.  I wanted to try two dishes and could not decide between them; fortunately, they have half portions available (adults have to eat at least one complete entree but two halves qualify) so I got a half of each.  The French toast was excellent; it was covered with rhubarb compote and its tart taste complemented the French toast nicely.  The "S'mores" pancakes were excellent too; this was a sweeter dish, basically very good chocolate-flavored pancakes, with not much taste to the graham cracker crumbs on top.  There was also a toasted marshmallow on top, which was cute.  Given the acclaim and the restaurant's size, I was surprised to see empty tables even when I left around 10:00, so I asked about it; they said they don't get really busy until around 10:30 or 11:00, and that applies to Sunday as well as Saturday.  They accept cash only, but there's an ATM inside.  Jam
937 N. DAMEN AVENUE
CHICAGO, IL 60622
OPEN DAILY | 7AM TO 3PM 
(CLOSED TUESDAYS)
(773) 489 0302 
</content><char_count>1329</char_count><word_count>240</word_count></reply><reply><id>5749271</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-07-11</date><time>09:20:00</time><content>
 This morning I had breakfast/brunch at Milk and Honey Cafe in Wicker Park.  This is a seven-day-a-week breakfast restaurant (also open for lunch and dinner, with a savory menu).  I had wanted to try it after seeing their French toast in the Tribune article on that subject ( </content><char_count>277</char_count><word_count>52</word_count></reply><reply><id>5908580</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-09-12</date><time>13:55:00</time><content>
 In my ongoing investigation of places for brunch - hey, it's a tough job, but somebody's got to do it!  :)  - today I went to Southport Grocery and Cafe in Lakeview, about half a mile west of Wrigley Field.  It was very good!  Southport Grocery occupies a narrow storefront on the west side of the street, with sidewalk seating in nice weather to supplement the seating inside.  It really is both a grocery and a cafe, although I would call it a &quot;deli&quot; and a cafe, rather than a grocery, because the items they have to go consist of prepared foods (mostly baked goods) and packaged goods (wine and specialty foods) with no fresh produce or meats the way the term &quot;grocery&quot; might imply.  When you walk in, there are some tables in the front, and then two long narrow aisles to the rear where there are more tables.  Along the right side of the right aisle is a row of tables with a long bench along the wall; along the left side of the left aisle is the cashier and the carry-out counter; and in between is a long row of shelves with the packaged goods.  Much of the seating is rather cramped, and the room is quite noisy, but those are the result of their success, which is due to the high quality and good value they offer.  When I arrived around 11:45, I was told there was a choice of immediate seating at a sidewalk table in the sun, or a 25-30 minute wait for another table.  I said that I was happy to wait for a table inside or outside, but not in the sun.  After waiting 15 minutes, I was seated.  When I was leaving around 1:00, it was starting to empty out and there was no wait.  I asked the hostess what typical times to avoid waiting were, and she said that it starts around 9:30 in the morning on Sundays (which seems to apply almost everywhere) and there's often a wait as late as 2:00.  Southport Grocery is open for dine-in and carry-out seven days a week, from early in the morning (7 a.m. weekdays, 8 a.m. weekends) till late in the afternoon (5 p.m. Saturdays, 4 p.m. other days).  There is a single menu available all day, with breakfast specialties (including the items I had) as well as lunch items like burgers, sandwiches, and salads.  I had an omelet and tried two of the sweet items.  The omelet was spinach-artichoke-tomato-jalapeno-cream cheese.  I enjoyed it; it was a nice blend of those flavors.  Because they want to keep their kitchen efficiently turning out food, they ask customers to stick to the pre-designated omelets with no variations in ingredients, and I suspect it is for this reason that the level of jalapeno was rather minimal (as was the artichoke flavoring).  Then, on to the sweets!  They offer a &quot;pancake taste&quot; of any of their pancakes at a low price of $4, and I loved the sound of one in particular.  Quoting from their menu: &quot;bread pudding pancakes &#183; a pancake made with gooey bread pudding topped with cinnamon-sugar butter &amp; a side of vanilla custard sauce (featuring our house-made cinnamon-sugar butter from the grocery)&quot;.  And that's exactly what it was!  It's hard to describe because it's an unusual item, one I haven't seen anywhere else... but think of it as a thick pancake, with the thin outside layer cooked and bready like a pancake, but most of the middle dense and moist like bread pudding.  Both accompaniments complimented it perfectly, the rich cinnamon-sugar butter and the absolutely wonderful vanilla custard sauce, which was similar to the creme patissiere (pastry cream) filling of an eclair from a good French bakery.  It was superb.  I also tried this: &quot;the grown-up pop tart &#183; warm &amp; filled with berry preserves, marscapone cheese and roasted vanilla walnuts (featuring preserves &amp; our house-made roasted vanilla walnuts from the grocery)&quot;.  It too was very good, and in fact similar to a folded over and stuffed version of the bread pudding pancake, right down to the bready outer layer and the dense, moist inner layer.  However, next time I'm going straight to the bread pudding pancake, because the accompaniments really make that dish one that will &quot;wow&quot; any lover of sweet dishes.  From reading the media articles in the waiting area and looking around the place, it seems that they are known for their cupcakes.  I didn't get any, so I can't comment on them.  (FWIW, cupcakes do absolutely NOTHING for me, and I just don't &quot;get&quot; the excitement over them, anywhere - but hey, if you like cupcakes, by all means please enjoy them, and now you know that this is a place known for them.)   So that was what I had.  I really enjoyed my brunch at Southport Grocery.  The food was excellent and interesting, and I absolutely LOVED the bread pudding pancake.  The only real downside is the same as almost any breakfast restaurant that doesn't take reservations: you're likely to have to wait to be seated if you arrive on a Sunday morning between 9:30 and 1:30.  </content><char_count>4845</char_count><word_count>901</word_count><reply><id>5908856</id><author>uhockey</author><date>2010-09-12</date><time>16:18:00</time><content>
 Returning to Chicago in early November for the SOFA show - Southport Grocery and Cafe just jumped to #1 on the breakfast/brunch list due to the Bread Pudding Pancakes - two of my favorite things going head to head......  </content><char_count>223</char_count><word_count>42</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>5927944</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-09-20</date><time>13:34:00</time><content>
 Yesterday I had brunch at </content><char_count>28</char_count><word_count>7</word_count><reply><id>5928016</id><author>lbs</author><date>2010-09-20</date><time>13:57:00</time><content>
 $40 doesn't seem that outrageous considering what you got.   I'd spring for that seeing that isn't steamed scrambled eggs and overcooked bacon in chafing dishes like a lot of buffets.  Thanks! 
</content><char_count>196</char_count><word_count>36</word_count><reply><id>5928108</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-09-20</date><time>14:45:00</time><content>
 :)   Just to put that $40 into perspective...  You'll pay less at most a la carte brunches, but you won't be getting all you can eat.  Most buffets don't have the level of quality of the food at Shaw's.  The higher-end restaurants that do a luxurious buffet Sunday brunch, like NoMI in the Park Hyatt, Seasons in the Four Seasons, or the Lobby in the Peninsula, are all charging $60-70 per person these days.  I can't name a single restaurant with an all-you-can-eat buffet comparable in both quality to Shaw's at anywhere near the price. 
</content><char_count>542</char_count><word_count>103</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6180139</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-02</date><time>16:10:00</time><content>
 Sunday brunch at Eve - BAD
Sunday brunch at Caf&#233; des Architectes - EXCELLENT  Today we had a reservation for brunch at Eve.  When we arrived, they were full and did not have a table available for us.  We were waiting ten minutes past the reservation time, and noticed that the room was INCREDIBLY LOUD, with everyone shouting at each other to be heard.  No thanks.  So at that point we cancelled our reservation and left.  We went around the corner to Caf&#233; des Architectes, where I have eaten numerous times for dinner and always enjoyed it immensely.  They were able to seat us immediately, without a reservation, for their a la carte brunch.  And although almost all the tables were occupied, the dining room was not terribly noisy at all.  We have been there before; the dining room is on the ground floor and is part of the curved glass fa&#231;ade of the gorgeous Sofitel.  The menu includes breakfast dishes (both savory and sweet), lunch dishes, and a &quot;brunch sampler&quot; for $25.  I got the latter and really loved it.  It includes small portions of a variety of items for each course.  It started with three small glasses of fresh juice, each topped with a piece of fruit indicating one of its ingredients.  One was Cape Gooseberry (grond cherry), which was slightly tart and had a very thick consistency, like a smoothie.  Another was pineapple and had a strong herb flavor which may have been from fresh mint leaves.  The last was blackberry and was the sweetest of the three.  I really enjoyed the variety of flavors and textures.  The second course consisted of small portions of three dishes and a large portion of the fourth.  The small ones were the smoked salmon napol&#233;on (delicious, smoked salmon on crackers with a bit of cr&#232;me fraiche), brioche French toast with caramelized apples (also delicious), organic avocado and tomato tian, red Tobiko caviar, pistachio oil (also delicious, think of it as guacamole topped with caviar).  The big dish was spicy scrambled Eggs with chorizo, served in a cast iron skillet, very good.  The final course consisted of three smallish desserts: vanilla panna cotta with berries, spice cake, and a chocolate mousse cake topped with nutty crispies.  All were excellent.  The brunch sampler also included coffee or tea.  I really loved it because it included so many different things and everything was delicious.  It was also a great value considering all that was included.  My dining companions got conventional lunch-type dishes (ahi tuna topped nicoise salad, and barramundi as the plancha fish of the day) and enjoyed them as well.  All dishes came with a basket of the most scrumptious French baked goods you'll find anywhere - a sweet brioche, croissants (chocolate, raisin, and plain), a small baguette, and an apricot danish.  Service was friendly and efficient, and the entire experience was very positive.  I enjoyed it and I thought Caf&#233; des Architectes's brunch was excellent.  Caf&#233; des Architectes
In the Sofitel Chicago Water Tower
20 East Chestnut Street
Chicago 60611
312-324-4000
</content><char_count>3045</char_count><word_count>536</word_count><reply><id>6182731</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>15:30:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; Sunday brunch at Eve - BAD  Eve has closed: </content><char_count>49</char_count><word_count>13</word_count><reply><id>6212247</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>17:04:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; Today we had a reservation for brunch at Eve
.
.
.
&gt;&gt; We went around the corner to Caf&#233; des Architectes  Coincidentally, Martial Noguier, the former executive chef at Cafe des Architectes, will be the executive chef at Bistronomic, the restaurant which is planned for the location where Eve formerly operated.  More info at </content><char_count>329</char_count><word_count>56</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6180639</id><author>barenakedlizzie</author><date>2011-01-02</date><time>19:48:00</time><content>
 I'd recommend </content><char_count>16</char_count><word_count>4</word_count><reply><id>6180806</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-02</date><time>21:21:00</time><content>
 I'd never heard of Juicy, and their website doesn't appear to work.  From the listing on Metromix, it sounds like it's a wine bar...?  The location may work against them; River West is not as lively as River North, which has its own wine bars (Pops for Champagne, Bin 36, etc).  I'd recommend Sable for artisanal cocktails.  The mixologists come from the Violet Hour, and you can combine those drinks with the great cooking of Chef Heather Terhune.  It's not necessarily a brunch dish, but don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee! 
</content><char_count>533</char_count><word_count>99</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Knife Sharpening - Avoid Sur La Table</title><id>2442141</id><author>stephenzr</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>06:22:00</time><content>
 If you want your knifes to actually be sharp, avoid Sur La Tables knife "sharpening".  First off, it's over priced.  They charge by the inch.  Secondly, and most importantly, they don't get them sharp.  What is the point if they aren't going to sharpen them.  Sure, you'll leave with fancy little bag and your knifes in branded cardboard sheaths, but they won't be any better then when you brought them in.  
I wasted my money on this service earlier this year but they wouldn't give me a refund over the phone and living in Lincoln Square I hadn't had the occasion to stop back by the Lincoln Park store for a refund.  Thanks guys.  
The good part of this is that I too the advice and drove down to Northwest Cutlery on Lake street.  It's in warehouse section underneath the green/pink line tracks.  They know what they're doing!  They use large spinning stone sharpeners and it's 3.50 per knife, no matter the length.  My knifes have never been so sharp and I'm loving cooking those pesky green onions again. 
</content><char_count>1014</char_count><word_count>193</word_count><reply><id>2442318</id><author>wak</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>07:38:00</time><content>
 I agree 100%.  Sur Le Table did mine once and I didn't notice any improvement.  Fortunately they did it for free, so I literally did get what I paid for.  Went to NW Cutlery on Lake and my chef's knife is like new again.  FYI, they also stock the full line of MAC knives which are used by many top chefs (Thomas Keller, Charlie Trotter, etc.) as well as an intersting selection of chef's supplies. 
</content><char_count>401</char_count><word_count>81</word_count></reply><reply><id>2442322</id><author>xena</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>07:40:00</time><content>
 I just received an email from sur la table today offering free knife sharpening!  Glad to see your post, I'll skip it. 
</content><char_count>122</char_count><word_count>25</word_count><reply><id>2442580</id><author>stephenzr</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>08:59:00</time><content>
 Yeah, I received that email this morning also.  That is what prompted me to write this post.  I'd been meaning to for a while, but this was good impetus. 
</content><char_count>157</char_count><word_count>33</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2442601</id><author>kcchan</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>09:05:00</time><content>
 Thanks for the recommendation.  I've been meaning to get my knives sharpened for a while, but had no idea where to do it since, as you know, it's hard to find a trusty place to get good knives sharpened.  Next time I head to Chicago, I'll have to go to Northwest Cutlery.  Do they sharpen knives while you wait, or do they take a few days? 
</content><char_count>343</char_count><word_count>71</word_count><reply><id>2442775</id><author>wak</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>09:44:00</time><content>
 They did it in a few minutes while I waited.    Lots of neat stuff to see while you are there too, including a box of beat up old butcher knives on a shelf near the floor - handles all nicked up, one with electrical tape around it.  Look like old props from a slasher movie.  Thought about getting one just to get a rise out of my wife next time I quarter a chicken. 
</content><char_count>370</char_count><word_count>81</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2443671</id><author>renov8r</author><date>2007-04-02</date><time>13:20:00</time><content>
 I know NW Cutlery and the are good at what they do BUT they will gladly take your $3.50 no matter what would be best for your knives... If you you have some VICTORINOX/Forschners , Dexters , older Laguioles or other "butcher style" blades that need some knicks cleaned up, deburred, and  re-edged head right over.  Similarly if you need a F. Dick Dickoron steel they have the best prices and selection. AND EVERYONE NEEDS A Dickoron!!!!  NW is NOT the place to go to have a Global (or other Asian) blade tuned-up, nor would I recommend taking a quality German knife to them.  I am sure this will sound pedantic, but the best way to approach knife sharpening is to FIRST begin by correctly steeling your knifes MORE OFTEN than you think they need it.  If you've already whacked up the edges seek out someone who truly cares about putting a better than factory edge on cutlery: </content><char_count>878</char_count><word_count>165</word_count><reply><id>2447077</id><author>stephenzr</author><date>2007-04-03</date><time>13:27:00</time><content>
 I took a pair of Wustoff Culinar knives in and they came back nice and sharp.  However, I don't have much to compare it to.  I just know they are sharp as all get out. 
</content><char_count>171</char_count><word_count>39</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>2448232</id><author>Francophile</author><date>2007-04-03</date><time>19:46:00</time><content>
 Can't speak to SLT's virtues/vices but can attest to the performance at NW Cutlery. In addition to quality knife sharpening and knife selection they have "industrial" cooking supplies at good prices. 
</content><char_count>203</char_count><word_count>33</word_count></reply><reply><id>2449188</id><author>bethann</author><date>2007-04-04</date><time>07:52:00</time><content>
 I've had good luck having my knives sharpened at the Wooden Spoon in Andersonville. They were cheap, quick and good (and convenient to Lincoln Square).  The Wooden Spoon 
5047 N. Clark
773-293-3190
</content><char_count>200</char_count><word_count>33</word_count></reply><reply><id>5548614</id><author>jdsboston</author><date>2010-04-15</date><time>16:52:00</time><content>
 How very embarrassing and true this headline is.  I couldn't agree more after my experience in 2010 I will avoid Sur La Table for my knife sharpening.  I just got off the phone with a store manager after all four of the knives I dropped off were badly scratched on the sides.  The lady at the cashier tried to tell me that "this is normal" for all knife sharpening.  I was shocked when I spoke with the Store Manager and she also tried to tell me that this is normal.  If you have a high end expensive set of knives and you value them and plan to keep them for the long term be sure that you do not take them to SLT.  I will never let them sharpen my knives again and will be taking my knives to a professional to have them sharpened properly by hand and properly finished and polished like a craftsman would.  I guess I am never shocked any more that people don't take care in maintaining other people's property when it comes to cars or housing repairs etc -- quality of workmanship has dropped.  But, when it comes to Sur La Table and sharpening of knives I expected hand sharpening and great care to be taken.  My knives look like they were run through an electric knife sharpener by a high school student with no training and no idea what they are doing and were not properly finished at all.  Avoid SLT for this cheap free promotional services and go to a knife sharpening pro.  As a longstanding SLT customer they have badly offended me here and I was shocked how flippantly they dealt with this issue.  "That's what happens when you sharpen knives using our machine" is not what you want to hear when some hack has scratched the hell out of a knife that you have owned for over 10 years and totally damaged a brand new Henckels that doesn't even have a year on it.  SLT should know better and offer better service to their customers than this.  I will try to attach a photo showing up close the scratching that was done to one of my brand new knives using their machine. Awful. 
</content><char_count>1989</char_count><word_count>389</word_count><reply><id>6208170</id><author>stephenzr</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>12:56:00</time><content>
 I'm sorry even more folks had damaged goods.  I have since purchased a DMT sharpening "stone".  I keep things honed well with this little guy and go much longer without finding a professional.  I have put some scratches on my Shun 7inch, but will live, since I can't be too indignant with myself. 
</content><char_count>300</char_count><word_count>58</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6208217</id><author>dlpens</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>13:09:00</time><content>
 I have only used Northwestern Cutlery for many years and they are probably the best sharpeners in Chicago not to mention that their assortment of fine cutlery is outstanding.  They usually finish my orders while I am browsing around and usually I find something to purchase.  I have also bought some very nice Shun knives there.  So ditto on your recommendation. 
</content><char_count>366</char_count><word_count>66</word_count></reply><reply><id>6211848</id><author>mkaufman</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>14:46:00</time><content>
 My experience with Northwest Cutlery was not as positive as others....yes, my knives came back sharp, however, they were significantly smaller....they had taken off between 1/16" to 1/8" of steel on each of my knives....this was fine for our inexpensive Chicago Cutlery knives, but I would be unhappy if it were a Global or premium european brand.....a boning knife would only have two or three sharpenings before being too small to use..... 
</content><char_count>445</char_count><word_count>74</word_count></reply></post><post><title>What's good near Hyatt Regency</title><id>5629759</id><author>dochoch</author><date>2010-05-20</date><time>09:43:00</time><content>
 We'll be back in Chicago in a couple of weeks, staying at the Hyatt Regency. What's good to eat nearby for dinner and breakfast? We like all kinds of food (except vegetarian/vegan), and not too upscale. Any good blues clubs nearby? 
</content><char_count>235</char_count><word_count>43</word_count><reply><id>5629817</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2010-05-20</date><time>10:08:00</time><content>
 See these discussions for recommendations near the Hyatt Regency:  Need to Impress - </content><char_count>87</char_count><word_count>16</word_count><reply><id>6211025</id><author>SLOLindsay</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>10:52:00</time><content>
 I have nothing to add except a) I love chowhound for this exact reason and b) nxstasy, you're my hero. :-)   Staying at the Hyatt Regency in a few weeks for a work trip. Have a rezzie at </content><char_count>189</char_count><word_count>42</word_count><reply><id>6211489</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>13:05:00</time><content>
 I've been to a couple of places I'd recommend within a few blocks of the Hyatt Regency since the post above.  Sable, in the Hotel Palomar, offers delicious contemporary American cuisine from Chef Heather Terhune, as well as artisanal cocktails.  Food prices are very reasonable and many items are available in small plates portions as well as full sizes.  Don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee!  </content><char_count>399</char_count><word_count>72</word_count></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Quiet, inexpensive working lunch in Loop - near State &amp; Monroe</title><id>6207428</id><author>wrigley32</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:46:00</time><content>
 Hello!  I'm looking for a place that will not be crazy at lunchtime in the Loop so I can meet someone and get a lot of work done at lunch.  It also needs to be inexpensive - preferably less than $10 per person.    It can be counter service with quiet booths or tables, or waiter service with same.  Any brilliant ideas?  Thanks for your help! 
</content><char_count>346</char_count><word_count>74</word_count><reply><id>6208423</id><author>solon</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>14:05:00</time><content>
 Well, the inexpensive places are not likely to be quiet, so there isn't a huge selection.   But you could try Berghoff's downstairs cafe on Adams, which is cafeteria-style.  The dining area is relatively calm and you can probably sit as long as you like. 
</content><char_count>258</char_count><word_count>49</word_count><reply><id>6208695</id><author>ferret</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>15:18:00</time><content>
 Ditto that.  Park yourself in a corner of their Bavarian paneled basement and you'll be fine. 
</content><char_count>97</char_count><word_count>19</word_count><reply><id>6210187</id><author>wrigley32</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>06:42:00</time><content>
 Thanks so much for the suggestion!  I've been to Berghoff, but not since they redid everything!  I'll check it out! 
</content><char_count>119</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6210349</id><author>ferret</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>07:46:00</time><content>
 Just be aware that the line for food gets long between 12 and 1, although it moves quickly (and the line is generally for the salads; you can cut ahead for cold and carved sandwiches or pasta).  Beyond that you can generally find seating for 2 and nobody will rush you out. 
</content><char_count>277</char_count><word_count>55</word_count><reply><id>6210787</id><author>wrigley32</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>09:54:00</time><content>
 Great to know!  Thanks a ton! 
</content><char_count>33</char_count><word_count>9</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>Middle Eastern, Turkish, or Moroccan in Lakeview or Lincoln Park</title><id>6190271</id><author>Hatori Hanzo</author><date>2011-01-06</date><time>06:56:00</time><content>
 Looking for a recommendation for good middle eastern, turkish, or moroccan food in Lakeview or Lincoln Park.  Ideally, I would like a place that delivers.    Thanks. 
</content><char_count>169</char_count><word_count>32</word_count><reply><id>6190678</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-06</date><time>08:57:00</time><content>
 Turquoise Cafe is in Roscoe Village and it's very good.  Their Metromix listing says they deliver.  </content><char_count>102</char_count><word_count>20</word_count></reply><reply><id>6190795</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-06</date><time>09:26:00</time><content>
 Sultans on Clark about 2500 North for middle eastern.  There's a moroccan place on Broadway that's spendy (mid-$15 per dish?) but good, north of Belmont a few blocks IIRC.  Both are dine-in, casual. 
</content><char_count>202</char_count><word_count>37</word_count></reply><reply><id>6201559</id><author>Karen1440</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>10:06:00</time><content>
 Fattoush (Lebanese) 2652 n. Halsted 
</content><char_count>39</char_count><word_count>7</word_count></reply><reply><id>6202560</id><author>Kjjunior</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>14:58:00</time><content>
</content><char_count>1</char_count><word_count>1</word_count></reply><reply><id>6210507</id><author>Springer</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>08:31:00</time><content>
 Check out A la Turka.   Fantastic Turkish food,   Around LIncoln and Belmont.  Probably no delivery though - but the kebabs and kofte are outstanding. 
</content><char_count>154</char_count><word_count>31</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Schwa closed last night.  Anyone know what happened</title><id>6198815</id><author>mcyentyre</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>07:39:00</time><content>
 We've had reservations for about a month and a half now for last night (Saturday night)- even confirmed a few days ago.  We get a call between 3:30p-4p yesterdat from Seth that the "restaurant will be closed this evening."  One of our foodie friend's wife had arranged this special surprise dinner at Schwa because that's just about the one place that no one of us has been able to dine at yet.  Talk about major disappointment!  All they mentioned afterwards is that if we decide to call back again to make another reservation, we should be able to tell them that we had a reservation on a night that they closed down the restaurant.    Anyone have any clue what happened???  BTW- we actually had a fabulous dinner at Balsan instead! 
</content><char_count>738</char_count><word_count>140</word_count><reply><id>6200326</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>18:31:00</time><content>
 I can't think of a single reason why a restaurant would call to tell you they were closed the same day as your planned dinner, unless they had a fire (which apparently they didn't).  Of course, this is not the first time Schwa has decided to close with little to no warning, leaving diners with long-held reservations in the lurch.  :( 
</content><char_count>339</char_count><word_count>65</word_count></reply><reply><id>6208352</id><author>Chargenda</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>13:45:00</time><content>
 I had the same thing last night! It was my birthday and they called me at 6pm to cancel my 8:30pm reservation. Talk about short notice. I had just bought a couple great bottles of wine and had made these plans back in November. Talk about a bummer on my birthday. I have been once before and really loved the whole thing and was super excited about my return. Seth told me to call back as well to reschedule, but after that I am just pretty frustrated. Something strange is going on there! 
</content><char_count>493</char_count><word_count>95</word_count><reply><id>6210483</id><author>aburkavage</author><date>2011-01-13</date><time>08:25:00</time><content>
 Schwa also cancelled on my birthday back in March citing some busted pipes.  I get the sense that Chef Carlson can't say "no" to personal friends, and so when one calls asking for a reservation last minute, an unfortunate "nobody" gets cut from the reservation list.    I was more than a little pissed, to say the least, when they cancelled on me for a bogus reason.  All of my frustration was relieved when I secured another reservation (much easier now that I had an excuse to be bumped to the top of the list) a couple months later and had the best meal I've eaten in Chicago! 
</content><char_count>583</char_count><word_count>114</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Alchermes</title><id>6209792</id><author>sbaldw2</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>22:45:00</time><content>
 Hello everyone,
I'm dying to make some castagnole for Mardi Gras. Unfortunately I have no idea where to find alchermes. Does anyone know a website or store in the Chicago area that carries it?
Thanks! 
</content><char_count>204</char_count><word_count>35</word_count></post><post><title>5 Days in Chicago...We Need Advice</title><id>6206800</id><author>martyonthemain</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>06:12:00</time><content>
 Hi Everybody,  My girlfriend and I have just booked a 5 day trip to Chicago, but do not know where to begin, in terms of food options. We will be staying in the magnificent mile area, however we will likely get subway passes, are up for a lot of walking (what better way to burn off the indulgent eating), and want to explore different neighberhoods (not just the uber-touristy ones). Also, we are on a budget.; although we are up for a bit of fine dining, the rest will have to be more budget-friendly.   Of course we want to get an authentic deep dish pizza - we have heard of lou M's, is this the best option? What are some other quintisential chicago foods, and what are the best places to get these. Also, we want to explore the city...what are some of the best foodie neighberhoods. As a last point, what MUST we do in Chicago (ie museums, areas, sights, etc). We greatly appreciate your help! 
</content><char_count>903</char_count><word_count>172</word_count><reply><id>6206832</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>06:31:00</time><content>
 There are previous discussions that will provide good places to start, to help you get the "lay of the land".  &gt;&gt; What are some other quintisential chicago foods, and what are the best places to get these.   This discussion tells what foods and places are unique or specialties in Chicago, foods that Chicago is particularly good at:  first time Chicago - </content><char_count>358</char_count><word_count>67</word_count></reply><reply><id>6207454</id><author>HoosierFoodie</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:52:00</time><content>
 I prefer Lou M.'s for deep dish.  Uno and Duo are fine examples.  Avoid Giordano's. 
</content><char_count>87</char_count><word_count>19</word_count><reply><id>6207482</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:59:00</time><content>
 I really love Giordano's; in fact, it's my favorite of all the Chicago deep dish pizzas.  However, there's a reason I don't recommend it to first-time visitors.  Giordano's features a double-crust "stuffed" pizza, rather than the single-crust deep-dish served at Uno/Due, Malnati's, and Pizano's.  It's a different style of pizza (and there are other places in Chicago that also serve stuffed pizza, including Nancy's, Bacino's, Carmen's, and Edwardo's).  So we have two different types of thick-crust pizza, with good examples found pretty much only in Chicago, and I love both types (of course, as a matter of personal taste).  Stuffed pizza started in the 1970s, whereas Uno started deep-dish in 1943.  First-time visitors would do well to start with the longer-standing "traditional" deep-dish of Uno/Due, Malnati's, or Pizano's.  On a second visit, come back and try the delicious stuffed pizza at Giordano's. 
</content><char_count>918</char_count><word_count>151</word_count><reply><id>6208428</id><author>HoosierFoodie</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>14:06:00</time><content>
 I appreciate the history lesson but I have been to Giordano's enough to know that it isn't as good, in my view, as the others.  If Giordano's isn't for the "first time visitor" it sure is loaded with tourists.    The last time we were there we were staying at a near-by condo.  We called and they told us 30 min.  So, we went in 30 min. and they told us that it would be another 30 min.  Then when we went the pizza was cold.  So, not only was the pizza bad so was the service.  And this wasn't our first issue as we have stayed near-by on many, many occasions. 
</content><char_count>565</char_count><word_count>122</word_count><reply><id>6208532</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>14:38:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; I have been to Giordano's enough to know that it isn't as good, in my view, as the others.  That's a matter of personal opinion.  I think their pizza is fantastic, the best I've ever had in my entire life, anywhere.  &gt;&gt; If Giordano's isn't for the "first time visitor" it sure is loaded with tourists.  That depends on which location you go to.  If you go to the Rush Street location, in the middle of the area with all the hotels for visitors from out of town, yes, Giordano's is going to have lots of tourists.  So will Uno and Due and Pizano's and Lou Malnati's in their River North locations.  For most people staying in that area, it makes a lot more sense to walk a few minutes to their locations nearby than to take a long trip by public transportation to go to locations where the crowd is primarily locals.  But if you feel that strongly about it, you can certainly go to their locations in outlying neighborhoods and suburbs where most of the crowd is locals.  (Just don't do this with Uno and Due, whose franchised locations outside of River North don't use the same recipes.)   In dozens of visits, I have never had a problem with the pizza at Giordano's.  It is always served hot and it is always ready within five minutes of when I have been told it will be ready.  I'm sorry you had a bad experience, but it's not consistent with all of my many visits to numerous locations of theirs. 
</content><char_count>1406</char_count><word_count>276</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6207651</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>10:48:00</time><content>
 Agree with HF.   I would also say avoid Ginos.    And I agree with nxstasy about deep dish being the entry and stuff pizza being a more difficult one to appreciate. 
</content><char_count>168</char_count><word_count>37</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6209622</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>20:32:00</time><content>
 I'm staying out of the Chicago pizza debate but check to see if your trip  is during Restaurant Week in late February - now that would be the perfect luck.  I'd definitely head over to </content><char_count>187</char_count><word_count>39</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Love Shakespeare.  Hate Navy Pier</title><id>6207519</id><author>dulcie54</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>10:08:00</time><content>
 We regularly attend shows at Chicago Shakespeare Theater, which is located within Navy Pier.  I am hoping to find a restaurant close to but not IN Navy Pier.  We are especially fond of dive-y, craft beer serving places, but I fear there is a dearth of those in the area.  Sort of casual, good food, maybe even small plates, reasonable wine list, open late. 
</content><char_count>360</char_count><word_count>69</word_count><reply><id>6207681</id><author>ferret</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>10:54:00</time><content>
</content><char_count>1</char_count><word_count>1</word_count></reply><reply><id>6207686</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>10:55:00</time><content>
 How close?  Within 3 blocks, there isn't much; I'd go to Fox &amp; Obel, the gourmet food store, which has a cafe as well as a sit-down restaurant now.  Another nearby choice is Sol y Nieve for tapas.  Within 6-8 blocks, there are hundreds of places.  Coco Pazzo Cafe is an Italian bistro just that side of Michigan Avenue.  But I'd walk the extra few blocks to Sable, in the Hotel Palomar.  It's casual, Chef Terhune's food is delicious (don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee) and reasonably priced, many of the dishes are available in small as well as full portions, and they have artisanal cocktails as well as the normal full bar.  Another option near Sable that fits what you're looking for is Quartino, which specializes in Italian small plates, is casual, open late, etc.  Since you regularly attend shows there, I recommend trying all these places! 
</content><char_count>857</char_count><word_count>159</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Laksa in Chicago</title><id>6204625</id><author>dulcie54</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>10:48:00</time><content>
 I just returned from London, where I had Laksa for the first time.  I absolutely loved it, and would now like to find some places here at home to have it. 
</content><char_count>158</char_count><word_count>34</word_count><reply><id>6206193</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>19:43:00</time><content>
 I asked a friend who is originally from Malaysia and here's his reply: "Penang (in Chinatown) served great laksa but it burned down about 4 years ago and nothing has been put back in its place.  Have not heard of any other good Malaysian restaurants in Chicago.  The best laksa we've ever had is the assam laksa at Nyonya in NYC." 
</content><char_count>334</char_count><word_count>65</word_count><reply><id>6207449</id><author>dulcie54</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>09:52:00</time><content>
 Thanks for the response.  Surprised and somewhat disappointed that this is apparently not available in a city the size of Chicago.  I will keep searching though! 
</content><char_count>165</char_count><word_count>30</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Heavy / Table Cream available in Chicago</title><id>6206354</id><author>Iowegan</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:00:00</time><content>
 When i moved here three years ago, Dominick's carried "Heavy Cream", but they pulled it after a year or so. I can't find it at Jewel or Oberweis; nor can I find it at any Mexican supermarkets. Can anyone tell me where I can find it? I'm *not* talking about "Whipping Cream".  Thx! 
</content><char_count>284</char_count><word_count>56</word_count><reply><id>6206369</id><author>lls</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:06:00</time><content>
 Yes, </content><char_count>7</char_count><word_count>3</word_count></reply><reply><id>6206726</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>05:24:00</time><content>
 Can you say what the difference is between "heavy cream" and "whipping cream" and how heavy cream gets used?    I thought I had seen heavy cream either at Jewel or Whole Foods, but can't swear to it. 
</content><char_count>203</char_count><word_count>42</word_count><reply><id>6206851</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>06:42:00</time><content>
 Heavy cream typically has a higher fat content than whipping cream; however, there are no official standards for those grades in the United States.  The higher fat content means that it will whip quicker (and if you keep going, will become butter quicker, too).  I know I've seen heavy cream in routine food shopping - meaning, I'm pretty sure I've seen it at places like Trader Joe's, Costco, Sam's Club, Dominick's, Jewel, and Whole Foods.  Not that you will necessarily find it at ALL of those, but you will find it as SOME of those, and you don't have to go to a specialty gourmet store like Fox &amp; Obel. 
</content><char_count>611</char_count><word_count>115</word_count><reply><id>6206967</id><author>ferret</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>07:34:00</time><content>
 Costco had half-gallons of the Land o Lakes Heavy Cream last time I checked (3-4 weeks ago). 
</content><char_count>96</char_count><word_count>19</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6206761</id><author>badvegan</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>05:46:00</time><content>
 If you have a whole foods they often stock cream up to 41% which is considered heavy cream in the us. If you are looking for the 48% heavy cream (usually called double heavy in the resturant industry) which is used extensively in the uk then you need to either buy it through a food wholesaler such as US foods, or find an English market or pub that will get you some. 
</content><char_count>372</char_count><word_count>74</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Mexican- NOT IN CHICAGO</title><id>6182245</id><author>CyKick</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>12:52:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt;
Why does it seem that NO Mexican restaurants in the Chicagoland area offer "Carnitas" on their menus???
When I travel to other parts of the country, most seem to have this staple on their menu.
There is nothing as good as a crispy, yet juicy and tender chunk of roasted pork!!  Anyone??   &lt;&lt; 
</content><char_count>298</char_count><word_count>56</word_count><reply><id>6182574</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>14:34:00</time><content>
 You haven't been looking very hard.  :)   In general, you'll have a better chance at finding carnitas at taquerias, more so than the nicer Mexican restaurants.  There are taquerias all over town, with concentrations in Mexican-American neighborhoods like Pilsen.  And try the Maxwell Street Market on Sundays!  XOCO is Rick Bayless's take on Mexican street food, and you'll always find them on the menu there.  You can often find them at Frontera Grill next door; this week's dinner menu there has enchiladas de carnitas, available in appetizer (small plate) and entree portions.  </content><char_count>583</char_count><word_count>102</word_count></reply><reply><id>6182983</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>16:56:00</time><content>
 Roasted pork?
It's pork braised in lard, and most taquerias have it on offer. Many of the mid tier restaurants too. If you really want to get "authentic" (whatever that means,) go to one of the carnitas joints that proudly specializes in it. 
</content><char_count>245</char_count><word_count>44</word_count></reply><reply><id>6206765</id><author>badvegan</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>05:51:00</time><content>
 You should note that there are three types of carnitas de puerco depending on what part of Mexico, Texas, or California the cook is from. The first is cooked like chicharones (pork rinds) where it is dropped in hot fat and fried. The second is cooked on a rotisserie. and the third and my favorite is cooked on a disco (a disk like metal frisbee thing that was originally used to plow behind modern tractors but is taken and welded and used in the fashion of a wok) they are all very different though all incredibly good. 
</content><char_count>525</char_count><word_count>99</word_count><reply><id>6206903</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>07:02:00</time><content>
 Where in Chicago can I try types 2 and 3? 
</content><char_count>45</char_count><word_count>12</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Fresh Sardines</title><id>5313655</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2010-01-11</date><time>13:29:00</time><content>
 Anyone know if fresh sardines are available for retail sale anywhere in the city?  Outside the city?
Thanks in advance. 
</content><char_count>123</char_count><word_count>22</word_count><reply><id>5313827</id><author>ferret</author><date>2010-01-11</date><time>14:17:00</time><content>
 Dirk's can get them; give them a call. 
</content><char_count>42</char_count><word_count>10</word_count></reply><reply><id>5314956</id><author>scoob</author><date>2010-01-11</date><time>23:26:00</time><content>
 Whole Foods sometimes has them. Especially the monster store off of Clybourn. 
</content><char_count>81</char_count><word_count>14</word_count></reply><reply><id>5334020</id><author>Eldon Kreider</author><date>2010-01-19</date><time>13:46:00</time><content>
 The Fish Guy had a good supply of Portuguese sardines today included in ten-dollar Tuesday, otherwise $13.95 per pound.  The large Cermak Produce on North Kedzie almost always carries sardines, but there is a good chance that they are previously frozen.  The Fish Guy
4423 N. Elston Ave.
Chicago, IL 60630
(773) 283-7400
</content><char_count>323</char_count><word_count>53</word_count><reply><id>6199122</id><author>clb5</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>10:20:00</time><content>
 I've seen them at Treasure Island off Clybourn in the past two weeks. Can't vouch as to whether they were previously frozen or not. I hope the Fish Guy's are fresh; for almost $14 a pound they'd better be. 
</content><char_count>209</char_count><word_count>41</word_count><reply><id>6206375</id><author>lilmomma</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:09:00</time><content>
 I think they have them at Fresh Farms or whatever it is called by the WALMART west of 94 on Touhy. 
</content><char_count>102</char_count><word_count>23</word_count><reply><id>6206398</id><author>lls</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:22:00</time><content>
 You can try H Mart on Touhy in Niles. ..they have wide selection of fish. 
</content><char_count>77</char_count><word_count>17</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6206730</id><author>chicgail</author><date>2011-01-12</date><time>05:26:00</time><content>
 I've gotten them at Whole Foods on Kingsbury (but they seem to only be available on weekends) and also at Dirk's on Clybourn. 
</content><char_count>129</char_count><word_count>25</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Razor clams</title><id>6182685</id><author>mjpd</author><date>2011-01-03</date><time>15:15:00</time><content>
 Does anyone know of any restaurants that serve them or markets that sell them fresh?  I have never seen them except in Italy and they were delicious! 
</content><char_count>153</char_count><word_count>30</word_count><reply><id>6192497</id><author>Eldon Kreider</author><date>2011-01-06</date><time>16:34:00</time><content>
 I have seen fresh razor clams at The Fish Guy Market.  Call ahead as they do not always have them.  An active thread on LTHForum has three other local sources: </content><char_count>162</char_count><word_count>34</word_count></reply><reply><id>6193602</id><author>citywayne</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>06:07:00</time><content>
 I've seen them frozen at H-mart in Niles.   I have not seen any fresh though. 
</content><char_count>81</char_count><word_count>19</word_count></reply><reply><id>6206402</id><author>lls</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:25:00</time><content>
 You can find them in </content><char_count>23</char_count><word_count>7</word_count><reply><id>6206433</id><author>Johnny West</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>21:54:00</time><content>
 I see a lot of places are getting the razor clams from Polly Creek (Alaska) where my brother and I used to fly in to fish silver salmon. 
</content><char_count>140</char_count><word_count>30</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Just good food</title><id>6206088</id><author>shelleybell</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>19:03:00</time><content>
 I will be travelling to Chicago in April to spend my BIG 50 birthday with the girls.  We will be eating out frequently, and would like a few recommendations in the $50/person range.   We are all pretty adventurous eaters.  We are staying on Randolph near Michigan Ave.  Anything within walking distance is ideal, but we will have a car if needed.  I have been to Frontera, </content><char_count>375</char_count><word_count>74</word_count><reply><id>6206185</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>19:40:00</time><content>
 $50/person can mean a lot of things, and can vary depending on quality and quantity of wine/alcohol as well as number of courses and whether it includes tax/tip.  Just sayin'.  So your best bet to verify prices to see how they fit is by checking the menus on the restaurants' websites.  I'll just leave out the megabuck places that definitely will be WAY over your budget.  I'd start with a couple of our contemporary American restaurants.  I really love Sable, in the Hotel Palomar, and the food there is very affordable.  They offer small as well as regular portion sizes of many of the dishes.  I stuffed myself with $30 of food and would order less next time.  The chef is Heather Terhune, who ran Atwood Cafe for ten years.  Don't miss the sweet corn creme brulee!  They also offer artisanal cocktails.  The other place in this category is Atwood Cafe; I haven't been there since Chef Terhune's departure, but AFAIK it's still good.  The atmosphere is quieter and more luxurious than Sable.  I'd also recommend our Italian places.  Three places near your hotel are worthy of consideration.  Cibo Matto is in the W hotel a couple of blocks away, and it's excellent.  The chef who started it, Todd Stein, recently left to go to the Florentine, another new place within walking distance.  And longtime stalwart Vivere is also very good and a few blocks from your hotel.  There are lots more choices when you get further away, but all of these should be within about a ten-minute walk from your hotel.  If I had to name one of these as "don't miss" it would be Sable. 
</content><char_count>1572</char_count><word_count>298</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Asian tasting menu</title><id>6204378</id><author>brinata</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>09:45:00</time><content>
 I am having tip of the tongue syndrome.  I am trying to remember the name of an Asian restaurant that does tasting menus in Chicago.  The chef apparently talks to the diners and then designs each course of the menu specifically for their tastes.  Does this description ring a bell with anyone? 
</content><char_count>297</char_count><word_count>57</word_count><reply><id>6204826</id><author>ferret</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>11:44:00</time><content>
 Arun's? 
</content><char_count>11</char_count><word_count>3</word_count><reply><id>6206119</id><author>brinata</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>19:16:00</time><content>
 That's it!  Thanks a bunch! 
</content><char_count>31</char_count><word_count>8</word_count></reply></reply></post><post><title>Appetizer shops</title><id>6205214</id><author>klb4</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>13:44:00</time><content>
 Where can I purchase appetizers for a party that are reasonably priced &amp; tasty?  I can cover a lot of ground - the location can be anywhere from NW Chgo to Deerfield.  I've purchase all that Trader Joe's has to offer but would like to try something different.  I've heard of </content><char_count>277</char_count><word_count>56</word_count><reply><id>6205639</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>16:07:00</time><content>
 There are lots of places.  The most cost-effective can be found in the freezers at Trader Joe's, Costco, and Sam's Club.  Beyond that, Foodstuffs (locations in Glencoe, Glenview, and Evanston) has some, fresh as well as frozen.  And so does Sunset Foods in Northbrook, Lake Forest, Highland Park, and Libertyville.  I think Zier's, the great butcher shop in Wilmette, has some frozen ones.  Or you could just get some fresh shrimp at Burhops in Wilmette or Glenview. 
</content><char_count>470</char_count><word_count>84</word_count></reply></post><post><title>where have all the lime leaves gone</title><id>5874499</id><author>matthucke</author><date>2010-08-29</date><time>07:55:00</time><content>
 It's been a few years since I did any serious Thai cookery, but I'm planning a dinner for some friends tomorrow (we have a group of six with a weekly rota, and it's my turn), and I wanted to get it right, so yesterday I set out for Broadway and Argyle, with an ingredient list covering half a page of notebook paper.  I found everything I needed except kaffir lime leaves (makrut).  These are generally easy to spot as they have a distinctive double-leaf shape; attached at the point of an almond-shaped dark green leaf is another one just like it.  When I've found them in the past, they were usually on styrofoam trays covered with clingfilm.  At my first stop, </content><char_count>666</char_count><word_count>127</word_count><reply><id>5875104</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2010-08-29</date><time>13:46:00</time><content>
 Off and on, they are outlawed. I'm not sure why, you can do a search and find the reasons. I've heard that this year is one of those years. I went on a search at H mart a few weeks ago - none.
You can buy them mail order, or from ebay, but they cannot come from certain areas. Seriously. Weird, but if you search, you'll find the reasons. I still have some left in the freezer from a few years ago, so I'm not stressing about it yet, but I'll have to order some soon myself 
</content><char_count>477</char_count><word_count>98</word_count><reply><id>5876432</id><author>matthucke</author><date>2010-08-30</date><time>07:45:00</time><content>
 Oh, how awful.  More officious meddling in our lives for no good reason... I went through Vegemite withdrawal a few years ago for the same reason, and had two kilos of it shipped in from an ebay seller in Australia in a plain brown wrapper.  That's a bit harder to do with something that must be consumed fresh!  I suppose I'll try a tea bag full of lime zest, and a bit of juice.  thanks - at least now I know I'm not a completely incompetent shopper, they really *had* vanished from those four shops. 
</content><char_count>506</char_count><word_count>101</word_count><reply><id>5876482</id><author>MikeG</author><date>2010-08-30</date><time>08:03:00</time><content>
 Whether it's a good reason depends on your perspective, I guess, but the trees - like all other citrus and some other species - harbor citrus canker which is considered to be a serious problem for the citrus industry.  Citrus-growing states do sometimes take draconian measures to protect the "mainstream" citrus industry, but when they go so far as to run around chopping down peoples' backyard grapefruit trees to stop outbreaks, good luck complaining because we can't easily get Thai lime leaves! (lol)  At first it was Florida  and everyone talked about eventually getting leaves from California, but they may have started regulating them too, for all I know - this has been going on for years now... 
</content><char_count>708</char_count><word_count>123</word_count><reply><id>5876590</id><author>matthucke</author><date>2010-08-30</date><time>08:44:00</time><content>
 That does sound reasonable!  Thanks for the info.  My curries will be flavoured with lime zest instead, for the foreseeable future. 
</content><char_count>135</char_count><word_count>25</word_count><reply><id>5876958</id><author>MikeG</author><date>2010-08-30</date><time>10:44:00</time><content>
 Or you can buy seeds on Ebay and grow one. :)  The scientific name is Citrus hystrix. 
</content><char_count>89</char_count><word_count>20</word_count></reply><reply><id>5894466</id><author>3blairs</author><date>2010-09-06</date><time>12:55:00</time><content>
 I have a Kaffir lime tree, been growing for 7 years--I'd be happy to get some leaves to you. Maybe they could be mailed? Let me know if you are interested. 
</content><char_count>159</char_count><word_count>33</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6205117</id><author>marzlet</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>13:12:00</time><content>
 My husband and I went on a similiar hunt for the limes leaves that never were found in Chicago.  Instead, we went to almighty Amazon and still have some in our freezer.  Great quality for a great price and the convenience!!
</content><char_count>226</char_count><word_count>44</word_count></reply><reply><id>6205309</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>14:17:00</time><content>
 They are available again. I bought some at teh market on Broadway just N of Lawrence a few months ago. 
</content><char_count>106</char_count><word_count>22</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Yu sang (&#39770;&#29983;) in Chicago</title><id>6198720</id><author>huiray</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>06:21:00</time><content>
 Are there any restaurants in Chicago serving yu sang (&#39770;&#29983;) ?  This is the raw fish salad of Cantonese/Chiu Chow origin, traditionally served at Chinese New Year.  I recently learned that it has been available in some SF restaurants for years, even year-round (not sure about Manhattan)...and wondered about Chi-town, which is much closer to me...    Thanks. 
</content><char_count>360</char_count><word_count>64</word_count><reply><id>6204459</id><author>huiray</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>10:06:00</time><content>
 &lt;bump&gt;  Anyone? 
</content><char_count>19</char_count><word_count>5</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Best fish tacos in Chicago area</title><id>6177918</id><author>easknh</author><date>2011-01-01</date><time>15:17:00</time><content>
 Looking for recommendations of best fish tacos in the Chicago area.  Please include descriptions of type of fish and how it is prepared.  Thanks for the help. 
</content><char_count>162</char_count><word_count>31</word_count><reply><id>6186368</id><author>blue_blanket</author><date>2011-01-04</date><time>20:33:00</time><content>
 I really like the ones at Garcia's on Western. They are grilled tilapia (I'm pretty sure it's tilapia). They serve them with your choice of corn or flour, and come with a guacamole and mayo on the side. 
I love that the fish is not breaded or fried. 
</content><char_count>253</char_count><word_count>50</word_count><reply><id>6199096</id><author>clb5</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>10:07:00</time><content>
 Thank you for the recommendation.  I had excellent fish tacos in Cozumel in 1995-96. They were were either lightly saut&#233;d (no batter) or a room-temperature ceviche. Never had anything like them since, and the most batter-based fried ones are an abomination. 
</content><char_count>261</char_count><word_count>44</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6192113</id><author>Tim N</author><date>2011-01-06</date><time>14:31:00</time><content>
 Big &amp; Little's has great fish tacos (939 N Orleans) 
</content><char_count>55</char_count><word_count>12</word_count><reply><id>6204348</id><author>zgwarnki</author><date>2011-01-11</date><time>09:36:00</time><content>
 I second the recommendation of Big &amp; Little's for fish tacos. They grill a large piece of mahi-mahii and then squirt some home-made spicy mayonnaise type sauce on it and serve it over shredded cabbage/greens. It's great. They also do fried fish tacos - specifically soft shell crab and catfish. Beware - cash only, limited seating and no air conditioning (not a problem now but last summer - Whew!) 
</content><char_count>402</char_count><word_count>71</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6195266</id><author>Lance Corvette</author><date>2011-01-07</date><time>14:54:00</time><content>
 Burrito House on Lincoln just south of Addison.  Fish is tilapia and it's prepared by a Mexican guy behind the counter. 
</content><char_count>123</char_count><word_count>24</word_count><reply><id>6198870</id><author>gordeaux</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>08:16:00</time><content>
 That might be the funniest description of a "food preparation" I've ever heard! 
</content><char_count>83</char_count><word_count>15</word_count><reply><id>6201320</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>08:48:00</time><content>
 Hate to recomend an "american" place, but the Oyster Bar at Shaw's makes a great blackened fish taco. 
</content><char_count>105</char_count><word_count>20</word_count></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6202684</id><author>amoncada</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>15:44:00</time><content>
 Feast in Bucktown serves up some of the best blackened (not breaded) fish tacos, seriously good!  I recall having decent fish tacos at Los Nopales. 
</content><char_count>151</char_count><word_count>28</word_count></reply></post><post><title>Condensed Chicago Food Must Haves</title><id>6196245</id><author>Gorp512</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>12:42:00</time><content>
 I will be headed to Chicago from Philly in March and will only have about 4 days of real food exploration on my trip.  I wanted to fill my days and nights with real winners and uniquely Chicago food experiences. Here is what I have so far;  Day 1  Lunch- Probably will be getting in around this time, any recs of a quick bite? I am looking for a real Chicago dog place. Somewhere locals would go. I don't think I can make it out to Hot Dougs.  Dinner-Girl and the Goat, Purple Pig, or Publican?  Day 2  Lunch- I may be flying this one solo, so another street food/hole in the wall spot would be nice. Italian Beef?  Dinner- Celebrating a birthday and am looking for a quiet, comfortable, and memorable place. I am thinking </content><char_count>725</char_count><word_count>145</word_count><reply><id>6196504</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>06:59:00</time><content>
 Sounds like you've already done a lot of research!  Here are thoughts about what you've laid out.  &gt;&gt; Lunch- Probably will be getting in around this time, any recs of a quick bite? I am looking for a real Chicago dog place. Somewhere locals would go. I don't think I can make it out to Hot Dougs.  Portillo's is always a great choice.  Not the only choice, but one of the most popular places among locals.  Also, Portillo's has the advantage of being a great place to get Italian beef as well as Chicago hot dogs.  And the advantage of their location on Ontario being in the middle of the hotel district in River North/Mag Mile.  Another option, if you're looking for more exotic encased meats but you want to avoid the crowds at Hot Doug's, is Franks 'n Dawgs.  It's a little closer to downtown, too.  &gt;&gt; Dinner-Girl and the Goat, Purple Pig, or Publican?  The places with buzz, huh?  :)  It may already be too late to get a reservation at the Girl and the Goat for March, but if you want to try, do it NOW, on Opentable or by phone.  Purple Pig doesn't take reservations and waits for a table at dinner are excrutiatingly long; I recommend going there for lunch instead, when waits aren't so ridiculous.  The Publican isn't my favorite, but at least you can make a reservation without difficulty; when doing so, specify if you have a preference either for your own table for up to 6, or for seating at the communal tables.  &gt;&gt; Lunch- I may be flying this one solo, so another street food/hole in the wall spot would be nice. Italian Beef?  As noted above, you can combine your beef and dogs at Portillo's one day, and do Purple Pig the other.  &gt;&gt; Dinner- Celebrating a birthday and am looking for a quiet, comfortable, and memorable place. I am thinking North Pond. Any great places for drinks afterwards that would be nice to go to dressed up? Maybe Tru's dessert tasting? Or the Siganture Lounge? Not looking for something too crazy, just something memorable and special.  All great choices.  North Pond is great.  It's not overly dressy; business casual is fine.  TRU's dessert tasting is nice, and I've heard you can get it in the lounge to avoid the jackets-required policy in the dining room; check with them.  The Signature Lounge atop the Hancock has that great view, of course.  Here are two other places for drinks.  The Violet Hour in Bucktown has amazing artisanal cocktails; if you go there, be aware that there is no sign outside, it's just a doorway hidden in the building's facade.  Another option is Sable, in River North.  Sable also has amazing artisanal cocktails - not coincidental, since their chief mixologist is a veteran of the Violet Hour.  Sable also has terrific food; you can get anything from a full meal to some "small plates" of either the savory or sweet variety.  The sweet corn creme brulee is a standout.  &gt;&gt; I already have my reservation for dinner at Alinea, so this day will obviously be centered around that. I am unsure about how much to eat before Alinea, I don't want to rush through because I was starving, also don't want to be full half way through.   Don't be overly concerned.  Alinea has a lot of courses, but they vary in size, and they're spread over a long duration.  I wouldn't starve yourself all day beforehand; it's really not necessary.  &gt;&gt; Brunch/Lunch- Want to get to Hot Chocolate or Jam (or both) on my visit. Maybe this day  My choice between these two would be Jam.  Although I would choose Bongo Room first, if you haven't been there already.  And M. Henrietta (the new sister restaurant to M. Henry) if you don't mind traveling from downtown (it's right at the Granville el stop on the CTA Red Line).  &gt;&gt; Lunch-I am going to need to get Chicago pizza on this trip. Wanted to head out to Burt's Place, but probably won't be able to make it. I have something later this night so a big lunch/early dinner would be ideal. Uno?  The original Uno and Due are excellent.  So are Lou Malnati's (locations downtown on Wells in the west end of River North, and at 8th and State in the South Loop) and Pizano's (on State off the Mag Mile, and on Madison in the Loop).  Remember to phone ahead with your pizza order to avoid waiting 30-45 minutes while seated for your pizza to bake.  &gt;&gt; Misc.- Also would love recs for great cocktail bars/bars around the city. Will certainly be going to Violet Hour and Big Star one night. Anywhere else not to be missed?  See above re Sable.  Feel free to ask more questions, and enjoy your visit! 
</content><char_count>4492</char_count><word_count>855</word_count><reply><id>6197043</id><author>Gorp512</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>11:00:00</time><content>
 Thanks so much for the info.  I will most definitely look into Sable.  I wasn't too hyped about Girl and the Goat, Publican, and Purple Pig. We have some places in Philly right now doing those kind of things and they aren't necessary, but the Purple Pig sounds like a good place for lunch.  Some other Chicago-related things I forgot to ask. I was looking into possibly getting into an underground dinner party. I was looking into Xmarx.   Also, for the birthday dinner. By any chance, are there any exceptional chef's tables around town?  Not necessarily something fancy, but I know here at home we have some ambitious young chefs who set up cool chef's tables in their byo's, gardens, etc.   And this has nothing to do with food, but where could I find the best jazz in town?    Thanks!! 
</content><char_count>793</char_count><word_count>153</word_count><reply><id>6197106</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>11:24:00</time><content>
 &gt;&gt; the Purple Pig sounds like a good place for lunch.  The nice thing about that option is, I believe they offer the same menu all day long.  Which means you're getting "the real experience" even if you go for lunch.  &gt;&gt; I was looking into possibly getting into an underground dinner party. I was looking into Xmarx.  I've never been, and I don't see the appeal, at least not in terms of food compared with choosing from our many great restaurants.  If your desire is to use it as a means to meet others, maybe.  &gt;&gt; Also, for the birthday dinner. By any chance, are there any exceptional chef's tables around town?  A few, not many, and they are in established restaurants.  See </content><char_count>681</char_count><word_count>134</word_count><reply><id>6202424</id><author>Tim N</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>14:08:00</time><content>
 You can also try Segal's Jazz Showcase in Printer's Row.  great place and has been around for ages.  Not nearly as well known as the Green Mill.  Segal's is also convenient to Buddy Guys if you are interested in some live blues.
</content><char_count>231</char_count><word_count>46</word_count></reply></reply></reply></reply><reply><id>6197017</id><author>GraceW</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>10:47:00</time><content>
 With respect to the quest for Chicago Pizza, you will get different opinions from everyone, but in my opinion, Lou Malnati's is superior. In addition, I have found it is harder to get seated and get my pizza in a reasonable length of time at Duo's or Uno's. Besides, Lou's has the best crust (and I don't even usually eat crust). 
</content><char_count>333</char_count><word_count>63</word_count><reply><id>6197041</id><author>nsxtasy</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>11:00:00</time><content>
 When you phone in your order ahead of time, you'll be seated when it comes out of the oven (at the time you specify) at all of them - Uno/Due, Malnati's, or Pizano's.  All three are good, and all three are similar.  Which is not a coincidence!  Both Lou Malnati's and Pizano's were founded by sons of one of the principal players in the early decades of Uno and Due, and all three worked there for many years before the sons struck out on their own.  Depending on where you're located, one of these may be closer and more convenient than the other two.  Whichever one that is, that's where I'd recommend going. 
</content><char_count>614</char_count><word_count>120</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6197171</id><author>Gorp512</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>11:50:00</time><content>
 I also was wondering if anyone could tell me anything they may be hearing about Next/Aviary.  Any chance they are opened by March? I probably won't make it to Next, but would love to try Aviary. 
</content><char_count>198</char_count><word_count>39</word_count><reply><id>6197278</id><author>masha</author><date>2011-01-08</date><time>12:32:00</time><content>
 There was a post on the LTH forum the other day indicating that they are well behind the targetted opening date of 2/1 but I don't know what that means for March. 
</content><char_count>166</char_count><word_count>34</word_count></reply></reply><reply><id>6198588</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>12:20:00</time><content>
 I haven't been to an Xmarx event but they do look interesting - and a great way to explore unexpected food available in Chicago. And I would definitely second Sable - they have booths where you can view the kitchen - not sure if they will seat just 2 folks there when busy but you can ask.  On the Jazz front, consider Jazz Showcase - really lovely club. 
</content><char_count>358</char_count><word_count>71</word_count></reply><reply><id>6201804</id><author>ms. mika</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>11:04:00</time><content>
 One more place for great and creative cocktails is </content><char_count>53</char_count><word_count>11</word_count><reply><id>6202354</id><author>jbontario</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>13:46:00</time><content>
 Yes, to all and in the same vein as Drawing Room and Sable, you may want to try Gilt Bar in River North on Kinzie.  A little bit of a scene yet laid back with great food and drink.  Have had two very nice meals with superb cocktails.  Gilt Bar 230 W Kinzie (directly behind the merchandise mart) </content><char_count>298</char_count><word_count>63</word_count><reply><id>6203444</id><author>Siun</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>21:47:00</time><content>
 I've only been to Gilt Bar for drinks and snacks but those snacks were amazing. It was a sendoff for a colleague so prime afterwork time on a Friday and the place was packed but still quite enjoyable and I definitely plan a return for food. 
</content><char_count>244</char_count><word_count>48</word_count></reply></reply></reply></post><post><title>borlotti/cranberry beans</title><id>6199255</id><author>coldcream</author><date>2011-01-09</date><time>11:17:00</time><content>
 Does anyone know where I can find borlotti or cranberry beans dried?  We're traveling to Chicago in a couple of weeks and I can't get them locally (I could mail order them, but pay dearly and for shipping).  Also, I'm looking for Italian lentils as well.  Any thoughts would be helpful. 
</content><char_count>290</char_count><word_count>56</word_count><reply><id>6201550</id><author>Karen1440</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>10:03:00</time><content>
 You can get them at Treasure Island.  </content><char_count>40</char_count><word_count>10</word_count><reply><id>6202946</id><author>coldcream</author><date>2011-01-10</date><time>17:38:00</time><content>
 Awsome, thanks.  I've never been there.  I've been to Chicago many times as I used to have family there years ago, but I'm not overly familiar.  I'll check it out.  Also, have you (or does anyone else want to post) about ordering from ranchogordo?  What other beans should I get?  Anyone have a favorite? 
</content><char_count>308</char_count><word_count>62</word_count></reply></reply></post></overherd>